you want to know why we're lonely cuz
你想知道我们为什么感到孤独吗？因为
we've architected Our Lives to be lonely
我们自己构建的生活注定孤独。
we are social animals of course it's
我们是社会性动物，孤独当然会
hurting us and so the question is is
伤害我们。所以问题是，
what can you do and this is the one
我们能做些什么？这是
thing that I learned that was the
我一生中学到的最
greatest lesson I ever learned in my
宝贵的一课，也是
life the true skill that we've lost and
我失去的真正技能，
everybody's guilty of this this s cynic
每个人都犯了这个错误。
the bestselling author sought after
畅销书作家、炙手可热的
speaker and unshakable Optimist is back
演讲家、坚定不移的乐观主义者“愤世嫉俗者”带着
with one solution that aims to solve
一个旨在解决
some of the biggest issues we face today
我们今天面临的一些最大问题的方案回来了。
everyone's looking for biohack for all
每个人都在寻找能够解决
the problems that we're facing today
我们今天面临的所有问题的“生物黑客”方法，例如
Rising suicide Rising anxiety depression
自杀率上升、焦虑、抑郁、
addiction mental health and there's one
成瘾和心理健康问题。有一种“
bioh hack that's better than all of the
生物黑客”方法比
things that we're trying which is
我们尝试的所有其他方法都好，那就是
friendship but we are not good at making
友谊。但我们不擅长交
friends and we're not good at looking
朋友，也不擅长照顾
after friends there's an entire industry
朋友。有一个完整的产业致力于
to help people become better leaders to
帮助人们成为更好的领导者，
help us maintain better relationships
帮助我们维持更好的人际关系，
and there's no industry to teach us how
但却没有一个产业教我们如何
to be a better friend and yet people
成为更好的朋友。然而，
with close friendships are healthier
拥有亲密友谊的人更健康，
they live longer they better deal with
他们更长寿，他们更能应对
stress less likely to become addicted
压力，更不容易上瘾。
friendship is the thing that actually
友谊就是如此。 友谊才是真正
protects us so why aren't we
保护我们的东西，那么为什么我们不把
prioritizing our friendship it's because
友谊放在首位呢？因为
we actually don't know how to do it mass
我们其实不知道该如何维系友谊。大众
transportation technology social media
交通、科技、社交媒体等等，都
all of these things they've interrupted
阻碍了
our ability to make friends or sometimes
我们结交朋友的能力。有时，
we have old friends where the only bond
我们和一些老朋友之间唯一的联系
is time but is it a friend simply
就是时间。但仅仅
because you've known somebody for a long
因为认识很久就称他们为朋友，这算不算朋友呢？
time they give you no joy give you no
他们无法给你带来快乐，无法给你带来
inspiration and if you have good
启发。如果你拥有真正的
friendship you will not feel lonely so
友谊，你就不会感到孤独。所以，
yes friends are allowed to change and
朋友是可以改变的，
it's never too late to make a friend so
交朋友永远都不晚。那么，
how do I make friends I guarantee you
我该如何交朋友呢？我保证，只要
you will make friends by learning how to
学会如何待人，你就能交到朋友，就这么简单。
we've just hit 6 million subscribers on
我们的D of Co频道刚刚突破了600万订阅用户！
the D of Co um so me and my team would
我和我的团队
like to do something we've never done
想做一些我们以前从未做过的事情来表达我们的
before as little thank you and we're
一点谢意，我们
calling it The dire ofo subscriber
称之为“D of Co订阅用户
raffle and here is how it works every
抽奖”。规则如下：
episode this month we're going to pick
本月每期节目，我们都会
three current subscribers at random and
随机抽取三位现有订阅用户，其中一位将获得价值
we'll send one of you a 1,000 voucher
1000美元的代金券，另一位将获得
one of you tickets to come and watch the
观看
D SE behind the scenes live with our
D of Co特别节目的门票。 幕后直播，我们的
team and one of you will have a
团队将为你们中的一位提供
10-minute phone call with me to discuss
与我进行10分钟电话交流的机会，畅所欲言。
whatever you want to talk about if
如果
you're a subscriber you're in the raffle
你是订阅用户，你就自动参与抽奖了。
thank you from the bottom of my heart
衷心感谢你们让
for allowing me to do something that me
我有机会做我
and my team love doing so much it is the
和我的团队如此热爱的事情，这是
greatest honor of my lifetime and I hope
我一生中最荣幸的事情，我
it I hope it continues uh off into the
希望它能一直延续下去。接下来
Future Let's get to the
进入
[Music]
[音乐]
episode
环节。
Simon hi Stephen good to see you again
西蒙，你好，斯蒂芬，很高兴
good to see you again it's interesting
再次见到你。很有意思，
because we've had a lot of conversations
因为我们之前有过很多交流。在
and um ahead of the conversation today I
今天的对话之前，我一直在思考，目前我最
mind for me at the moment and subjects
关注的话题是什么？有哪些话题是
that I'm struggling to understand and
我难以理解、难以应对、难以
grapple with and find Solutions and
找到
answers to and the sort of macro picture
答案的？我脑海中目前的宏观印象是，
going on because the world has changed
世界发生了
quite profoundly and the struggle is
翻天覆地的变化，我们正面临着各种各样的困境，而这些困境也以
showing up in a variety of ways we're
各种方式显现出来，比如
seeing it in our mental health which I
我们的心理健康，我
know you refer to as mental Fitness
知道你称之为“心理”。
we're seeing it in suicidality we're
我们看到，在自杀率
seeing it in the the rise in loneliness
上升和孤独感加剧方面，健身问题也日益凸显。
which is something we talked about last
上次我们讨论过孤独感，
time but also now there's these other
但现在还有其他
forces at play like artificial
因素在起作用，比如
intelligence which feels like a threat
人工智能，它感觉像是一种威胁；还有
um in increas in digitalization and a
数字化程度的提高和
populist movements and strongman
人与人之间联系的减弱。你如何看待我们所处的这个时代？这是一个复杂的时代，我认为更重要的是，这是一个缺乏领导的时代。我们看到民粹主义运动和强人
leaders not necessarily because they are
领导人的兴起，这不一定是因为他们是
the great leaders of the day but because
当今的伟大领袖，而是因为
I think people are desperately lacking
我认为人们迫切需要
for meaning and purpose and to feel like
意义和目标，需要找到前进的方向。
people want to be led whether it's young
人们渴望被领导，无论是
protesting on their school
校园里的抗议青年，
campuses or whether during covid it was
还是新冠疫情期间的
anti vaxers or antim
反疫苗者或反
maskers you know whether it was brexit
口罩者，亦或是英国脱欧运动，
or you know I think they're all very
我认为它们本质上都非常
much the same whether it's the left side
相似，无论是左翼
of politics or the right side of
还是右翼，
politics which is they're all basically
它们本质上都是
anti-establishment
反建制
movements and you usually see
运动。
when people feel forgotten and left out
当人们感到被体制遗忘和排斥时，就会产生反建制情绪。
in other words they they perceive that
换句话说，他们认为
the establishment looking after for
体制只顾
themselves so I think we leave in we
自身利益。所以我认为，我们
live in visionless and leaderless times
生活在一个缺乏远见和领导的时代，
that's the big challenge of the day and
这是当今最大的挑战。
uh and so we find ourselves reactive to
因此，我们发现自己对
each other and against things but few
彼此和各种事物都做出了反应，但很少
people can say what they're for so many
有人能说出自己的立场。
of my guests have come here and then
我的很多嘉宾来到这里，在
after the conversation have turned to me
谈话结束后，都会转向我
and said they're concerned about their
说他们很担心自己的
younger child often they reference their
孩子。他们经常提到自己的
younger son because they talk about the
小儿子，因为他们谈到网络上
rise in the sort of toxic male
男性毒性
influences online um and it kind of
影响的增加。这和
coincides with what you just said about
你刚才说的
looking for leaders and now you know
寻找领导者有点吻合。你知道，
some of those leaders that were looking
有些所谓的领导者试图给
for offering us a blueprint of what it
我们提供一个“
is to be a responsible stable human that
负责任、稳定”的人的蓝图，
involves buying a Lamborghini having
比如买兰博基尼、娶
multiple wives and showing up in a
多个妻子、以某种
certain way and I've had so many
特定的方式示人。
conversations in fact one of my guests
事实上，我和很多嘉宾都进行过类似的对话。就在前几周，我的一位嘉宾给
the other the other week brought me a
我带来了一份名为《
dossier called heroic
英雄式
masculinity and um it was a woman and
男子气概》的资料。她是一位女性，
she says please can you have more
她说：“请问您能多做一些类似的
conversations about this subject and
对话吗？” 她跟我说了这件事，然后把这件事告诉了我。
passed it to me and the reason she's
她
saying that is because she's concerned
说这些是因为她担心
her son is growing up in a world where
她的儿子在一个不了解
he's not going to know what it means to
何为
be a good man or who are the role
好男人、不知道谁是
models like who are the strong male or
榜样的世界里长大，不知道有哪些坚强的男性或
female role models who are teaching us
女性榜样在教导我们
values who are teaching US
价值观、教导我们
service who's teaching us kindness and
服务、教导我们善良和
empathy in in leaderless times and lost
同理心。在这样一个没有领袖、迷失方向的
times we will follow things that make us
时代，我们会追随那些让我们
feel good right wealth makes us feel
感觉良好的事物，对吧？财富让我们感觉
feel good conspicuous consumption makes
良好，炫耀性消费让
us feel good because you get that hit of
我们感觉良好，因为它们能刺激
Serotonin and and dopamine this this is
血清素和多巴胺的分泌。这就是
the reason why I've become really
为什么我
fascinated by the concept of friendship
对友谊的概念如此着迷。
you know I haven't written a book in a
你知道，我已经很多年没写书了，
many years and so I've started writing
所以我又开始写作了。
again and uh I'm writing a book with a
我正在和
friend my friend will gadera um who
我的朋友威尔·加德拉（他
wrote unreasonable
写过《不合理的
hospitality and we've decided to write
款待》）合著一本书，我们决定写一本
about friendship because when you think
关于友谊的书，因为
about all of the problems that we're
想想我们
facing today mental Fitness Mental
今天面临的所有问题：心理
Health um Rising suicide Rising anxiety
健康、自杀率上升、焦虑和
depression addiction I mean take your
抑郁加剧……我的意思是，随便
list even people's obsession with
列举一下…… 人们痴迷于
longevity and everyone's looking for a
长寿，每个人都在寻找
biohack for all those things and there's
各种生物黑客手段来解决这些问题。但有
one biohack that's better than all of
一种生物黑客手段比
those all of the things that we're
我们
trying which is friendship people with
尝试的所有其他方法都更有效，那就是友谊。拥有
close friendships are healthier they
亲密友谊的人更健康、更
longer they have better coping
长寿，他们拥有更好的应对
mechanisms which means they better deal
机制，这意味着他们能更好地应对
with stress and I'll give you one an
压力。我再举一个
amazing thing so there's um a very
惊人的例子。有一个非常
famous experiment that's done I think in
著名的实验，我认为大约在20世纪80年代进行。
like the s all of our sort of
我们对
understanding of addiction is based on
成瘾的理解很大程度上基于
the study basically they put a rat in a
这项研究。基本上，他们把一只老鼠放在
cage and they gave it um plain water or
笼子里，给它喝清水，或者
they gave it water laced with drugs and
给它喝掺有药物的水。老鼠尝了
it tasted both it got addicted to the
两种水，结果它对掺有药物的水上了瘾，
water laced with drugs and eventually
最终
drank the that water until it died right
喝到死。
and so this became our understanding of
这就是我们对成瘾的理解。
addiction many years later not that long
多年后，
ago another scientist said hold on
不久前，另一位科学家指出，
there's a problem with this experiment a
这个实验存在一个问题。
rat like a person is a social animal and
老鼠和人一样，都是群居动物。
you took this social animal and you put
你把这种群居动物单独关起来，
it by itself and then offered it drugs
然后给它提供药物，人为地
so you created loneliness and then you
制造了孤独感，然后再给它
offered the drug right if you want to
提供药物。如果你
make it a good experiment you have to
想让它…… 好的实验需要
create the right context so what it did
创造合适的环境。
it created they created something called
他们创建了一个叫做“
rat Park where basically what they did
老鼠公园”的地方，基本上就是在
is they created a new cage filled with
一个新的笼子里放满了各种
things to do and mazes and wheels and
玩具、迷宫、跑轮和
and other rats and they were social and
其他老鼠，让它们进行社交活动。
the Rats tasted both Waters the one
老鼠们品尝了两种水：一种是
laced with morphine and the one that was
掺了吗啡的水，另一种是
just plain they taste and they drank
纯净水。它们喝了
enough of the morphine laced one to get
足够多的掺有吗啡的水，最终上瘾。
addicted and then they stopped it it
然后他们停止给老鼠喂吗啡，老鼠的
diminishes how much they drank and they
饮水量逐渐减少，最后
only drank the plain water so basically
只喝纯净水。所以，基本上，
when you have healthy relationships we
当我们拥有健康的人际关系时，我们就
are less likely to become addicted when
不太容易上瘾；而当
we are lonely we are more likely to
我们孤独时，我们更容易
create addiction right friendship is the
上瘾。友谊才是
thing that actually protects us and then
真正保护我们的东西。
if you look at even if you do become
即使你真的
addicted right let's take the the worst
上瘾了，我们来看看最糟糕的
case scenario so let's look at
情况，比如
alcoholism right alcohol ISM um we know
酗酒。我们都知道，
that to beat alcoholism you join AA
要戒酒，你需要加入匿名戒酒互助会（AA）。
Community we and everybody talks about
每个人都在谈论
the importance of community and finding
社区的重要性，以及如何找到
your community right but Alcoholics
自己的社区。
Anonymous knows that there's these 12
匿名戒酒互助会也知道，戒酒有12个
steps and if you master 11 of the 12
步骤，如果你能掌握其中的11个，你就能戒掉酒瘾。 十二
Steps the disease is probably going to
步疗法或许能帮
get you but if you master the 12th step
你摆脱疾病的困扰，但如果你能掌握
the final step you're more likely to
最后一步——第十二步，你就更有可能
overcome the disease so what's the 12th
战胜疾病。那么第十二
step the 12th step is to help another
步是什么呢？第十二步是帮助另一位
alcoholic to become someone's sponsor
酗酒者成为他的互助伙伴，
and in other words to become a friend in
换句话说，就是成为朋友，也就是融入
other words Community you find Community
社群。你会找到社群，
but then the the final step of beating
但战胜疾病的最后一步
the disease is a friend where where you
是找到朋友，
replace the community with a friend and
用朋友取代社群，这样
you have both and we think Community is
你就能两者兼得。我们通常认为社群很
the thing but it's not enough yes you
重要，但这还不够。没错，你
can create belonging with community and
可以通过社群和人际交往来建立归属感。
people where we started talking about it
我们之前讨论过，
where people are latching onto these
人们会加入
these anti-establishment populist
这些反建制的民粹主义
movements it's giving them a sense of
运动，这让他们感受到
community it's giving them a sense of of
社群的归属感，感受到
of shared Purpose with a group of people
与一群人共同的目标。
right but it's also providing um new new
但这些运动也提供了新的
social connections one of the things we
社交联系。我们
don't do is we are not good at making
不擅长的一点是，我们不善于交
friends and we're not good at looking
朋友，也不善于
after friends there's an entire industry
照顾朋友。现在有一个完整的行业
to help people like us become better
可以帮助像我们这样的人成为更好的
leaders I I I'm a part of it I write
领导者。我就是其中的一员，我还写过
books about it right there's an entire
相关的书。 现在有一个完整的
industry to help people be better
产业致力于帮助人们成为更好的
parents and if you're going to have a
父母。如果你要生
child if you got a child you got a child
孩子，或者你已经有了孩子，而你的孩子
with problems you know you read all the
又有问题，你知道，你读过所有
books about how be how to be a better
关于如何成为更好父母的书，但却
there are no books or precious few books
没有书，或者说极少有书
to teach us and there's no industry to
可以教我们
teach us how to be a better friend like
如何成为更好的朋友。也没有任何产业教我们如何成为更好的朋友，比如，
are you a good friend are you a good
你是一个好朋友吗？你
friend to your friends are your friends
对你的朋友好吗？你的朋友
good to you you know who do you do you
对你好吗？你知道，
call people when you are stuck and down
当你感到沮丧和难过时，你会给谁打电话？
or do you make Tik Tok videos by
还是你会自己拍TikTok视频？
yourself which you know and you get I
你知道，我
mean literally people who are depressed
理解，真的，很多抑郁的人会
make Tik Tok videos by themselves I
自己拍TikTok视频，我
don't know how many times they re-shoot
不知道他们为了发布视频寻求认同，反复拍摄了多少遍。
validation for their feelings but to
但是，给
call a friend and say the same thing
朋友打电话，倾诉
you're struggling with is actually more
你正在经历的挣扎，实际上要难得多。
difficult why doesn't the industry exist
为什么这个产业不存在呢？
because typically we take it for granted
因为我们通常认为这是理所当然的。是的，是的，
yeah yeah so the demand isn't there for
所以对
those kinds of things but that's what
这类服务的需求并不高。但这正是
that's the problem which is I think the
问题所在，我认为
demand is is is is there and we don't
需求是存在的，只是我们没有意识到。
realize it right like we know that our
我们明明知道…… 我们的
relationships fail and our marriages
恋爱关系会失败，婚姻也会失败，
fail so there's an entire industry to
所以才有了这样一个完整的产业来
help us maintain better relationships
帮助我们维持更好的关系。
will friendships fail and we think we
友情也会失败吗？我们以为我们是
friends yet we still struggle and feel
朋友，但实际上我们仍然会感到孤独和
lonely if you have good friendship you
挣扎。如果你拥有真正的友谊，你就
will not feel lonely you may have
不会感到孤独。你可能会有感到
moments of loneliness and in those
孤独的时刻，但在那些
periods you will pick up the phone and
时候，你会拿起电话
say to your
告诉你的
friend I need you I'm lonely and your
朋友：“我需要你，我感到孤独。”你的
friends will be there you will feel not
朋友会在那里，你会感到不再
alone right or um and you and I have
孤单，对吧？或者，嗯，你我之前也
talked about this about you will feel
讨论过这个问题，你会觉得
that someone will get in the mud with
有人会和你一起经历困境。
you and I think the problem is is we
我认为问题在于我们
don't give intention to Friendship we so
没有真正重视友谊，我们没有认真
think about it and you and I are both
思考过它。你我都犯过这样的错误，
guilty of this in fact I would argue
事实上，我认为
that everybody's guilty of this which is
每个人都犯过这样的错误。比如，
we've got plans booked with a friend
我们和朋友约好了
let's call it a lunch a work thing comes
午餐，但突然工作来了，
up we call up the friend I got a work
我们打电话给朋友说：“我有工作。”
thing and the reason we keep bumping our
我们总是取消和
friends is because they'll understand
朋友的约会，是因为我们相信他们会理解，
they're our
他们是我们的
friends so why aren't we prioritizing
朋友。那么，为什么我们不把
our friendships why aren't we saying to
友谊放在首位呢？为什么我们不对
the work thing I'm sorry I've got a
工作说：“对不起，我有事要忙。”
we would say sorry I've I've got an
我们以前会说“抱歉，我有个
appointment I can't make it so why don't
约会，去不了”，所以为什么不把
we treat our friends with the same
朋友也当成
intentionality that we treat any other
对待其他任何会议一样用心对待呢？威尔·加德拉（Will Gadera）
did for a friend that I thought was
为一位朋友做的一件事，我觉得非常
genius brilliant beautiful will gadera
天才、精彩、美好，
who I'm writing the book with um Will's
我和他合著了一本书。威尔的
friend's dad
朋友的父亲
died um will texted him and said
去世了，威尔给他发短信说：“
uh I feel for you I know what you're
我很理解你的感受，我知道你的处境，我
going through I lost my mom at an early
小时候也失去了母亲。
age um I'm sure you're being undated
我知道你肯定被
with calls and
电话和
texts so I'm not going to call you
短信淹没了，所以我今天不会给你打电话，
today but what I will do is I will call
但我会每天早上
you every single day at 9:45 a.m. do not
9点45分给你打电话。你不必非得
feel obligated to pick up I don't mind
接，不接也没关系，
if you don't but when you're ready know
但当你准备好了，要知道
that I'm calling you and for the next I
我会给你打电话。”接下来的
think it was 3 months 8 months something
三个月，或者八个月左右，
he called every single day at 9:45 a.m.
他每天早上9点45分都打电话。
and for the first week his friend didn't
第一个星期，他的朋友一个也没
pick up at all and then after the first
接，然后第一个
week he picked up every day and they
星期之后…… 他们每天都打电话，而且连续
talked every day for months like think
几个月每天都通话。想想看，
intentionality that somebody who loves
一个如此爱你
and cares about you so much that they
、如此关心你的人，
will call you every single day at 9:45
每天早上9:45都会打电话给你，
just so that you can see their name pop
只是为了让你看到他们的名字
up and the caller ID to know that you're
和来电显示，让你知道你
not alone I mean it can it brings me to
并不孤单。我的意思是，光是想想就让我
tears just thinking about it like how
热泪盈眶。
many of us are are that good a
我们当中有多少人能做到这样？
friend you know I want friends like
你知道吗？我想要这样的朋友。
that here's a good question like what's
这是一个很好的问题：朋友是什么样的？什么样的
a friend like what makes a good friend
人才算好朋友？
like I don't even know if we have a
我甚至不知道我们有没有一个
definition of that you know I've been
定义。我一直在
asking people and somebody said to me
问别人，有人对我说，
that's a real friend right and I got
真正的朋友就是在你困难的时候陪伴你、支持你的人。对吧？我又
thinking and I talked to somebody else
想了想，然后我和另一个人聊了聊。
she has a friend who she calls Mr shoden
她有个朋友，她叫他“肖登·
Freud because he seems to love when
弗洛伊德先生”，因为他似乎特别喜欢
things go wrong so in hard
事情出错。所以，在困难的
times he's always there he's always
时候，他总是在那里，总是在你身边，给你
shoulder to lean on he's giving advice
肩膀依靠，给你建议。
but in Good Times he's nowhere to be
但在顺境的时候，他就消失得无影无踪了。
seen and so what what happens is it
结果就是，这会
creates this horrible sort of
形成一种可怕的
codependent relationship that you want
共生关系：你想把
to keep the hard times because that
困难时期也留住，因为那个
wonderful human being is always there so
好人总是在你身边，所以
you never want to let go and you become
你永远不想放手，最终变得
codependent and so you realize that
依赖成性。于是你意识到，有
there's something called a fair wethered
一种
friend who's only there in the good
朋友只在
times but be equally cynical and
顺境中出现，而另一种朋友只在逆境中出现，你会同样感到愤世嫉俗和
suspicious of the fou weathered friends
怀疑，
because somehow it makes them feel good
因为逆境会让他们自我感觉良好，
about themselves but they're not there
但他们却不会在你顺境时陪伴你。
for the good times and so you realize
所以你开始思考顺境
versus bad time so
和逆境的价值孰轻孰重。
yes yes you and I have friends that in
没错，你我都有会在
hard times we would call them but I
困难时期打电话的朋友，但我
would bet money that you have even fewer
敢打赌，你会想在
blue and say I won an
毫无预兆的情况下发短信告诉他们“我得奖了”的朋友寥寥无几。
award right think about that like if
想想看，如果出了
something goes wrong I've got a group of
什么事，我可能有一群
friends probably I've probably got a you
朋友，大概有
know a dozen people I could say and say
十几个人，我可以告诉他们“
I need your help things have gone hard
我需要你们的帮助，事情糟透了，我
horribly wrong I I need your advice but
需要你们的建议”。但
if something amazing happens to me that
如果我遇到了什么好事，
that I'm going to text out of the blue
我可能只会给四个人发短信。
and go something amazing happened today
今天发生了一件很棒的事，我
and not feel like I'm bragging not feel
感觉自己不是在炫耀，也不是
like I'm trying to overwhelm them or
想压倒他们或者
prove them that I'm better than them but
证明我比他们强，而是
knowing that they will be so happy for
知道他们会为
me and so I've started thinking that
我感到高兴。所以我开始思考，
maybe a friend isn't just the person
朋友不仅仅是
who's there for you in the hard times
在你困难的时候陪伴你的人，
but the person you can go to in the
也是你在顺境中可以依靠的人。
great times think about that I have
想想看，当一切顺利的时候，我能依靠的朋友比遇到困难时能依靠的
fewer friends that I can go to when
朋友少得多。
wrong so are those my true friends so
那么，这些才是我的真朋友吗？
this is on the journey I'm on I'm trying
这就是我正在探索的旅程，我试图
to understand what friend means and I'm
理解朋友的意义，也试图
trying to understand the responsibility
理解
we have to look after those friends um
我们有责任去守护这些朋友。
you look at all the longevity studies
看看那些关于长寿的研究，比如
you know all the Blue Zone work sure
蓝区的研究，
they eat healthy sure they walk a lot
他们当然吃得健康，也走很多路，
but they also eat with each other
但他们也会一起吃饭。
whereas you look at some of the people
而那些
who are promoting sort of longevity and
鼓吹长寿、鼓吹各种
all of those bioh hacks and how you have
生物技术秘诀、鼓吹你必须以
to exercise the certain way and eat the
某种方式锻炼和饮食的人，
certain way you'll find a lot of them
你会发现他们中的很多人都很
are pretty unhappy people and pretty
不快乐，很
lonely people I don't think they're
孤独。 别以为他们能
going to live very long right so here's
活很久，对吧？那我就来个更劲爆的问题：从
one physiologically right what are the
生理学角度来说，哪些
most important organs to keep strong for
器官最重要，保持强健才能
longevity like we know the data right so
长寿？我们都知道数据，所以
I'll tell you what they are right number
我来告诉你答案。第一，
one heart obviously that makes perfect
当然是心脏，这很合理，对吧？
heart if you want to live a long time
想长寿就得有颗健康的心脏。
right second one lungs gotta have
第二，是肺，想长寿就得有
healthy lungs to live a long time cardio
健康的肺，还有有氧运动等等。
and all the rest of it right don't smoke
别抽烟，这
like we know that makes perfect sense
我们都知道，这很合理。
you know what the third most important
你知道第三重要的
organ is I didn't know I was going to
器官是什么吗？我本来
say the brain but the
想说大脑，但其实
thighs thigh muscles are the are the so
是大腿，大腿肌肉才是最重要的。所以，
if you have a healthy heart healthy
如果你有健康的心脏、健康的
lungs and healthy thighs statistically
肺和健康的大腿，从统计数据来看，
you're more likely to live longer I know
你更有可能活得更久。我知道
I said the same thing thighs do you want
我重复说了一遍，大腿。你想
to know why because historically thighs
知道为什么吗？因为从历史上看，大腿
are the most important muscle
是最重要的肌肉，
responsible for what motion walking
负责行走，对吧？
right not exercise Social going to visit
社交活动，比如去拜访
your friends before there were cars
朋友。在汽车和
before there were trains we had to walk
火车出现之前，我们只能步行去
to go visit our friends and so people
拜访朋友。
who are mobile if you're more mobile
如果你行动方便，就
you're more likely to main friend
更有可能结交朋友，
maintain friendships which means you're
维持友谊，这意味着你
likely to live longer so the three most
可能更长寿。历史上，对人类而言，
important organs to keep healthy
保持健康的三大重要器官是
historically as human beings heart lungs
心脏、肺
and thighs for Mobility thighs for
和腿部。腿部对行动能力至关重要，对
sociability
社交能力也同样重要，这一点
which I think is amazing that we never
我们以前从未
thought about so all of these things
想到，真是不可思议。所有这些
that you know technology has
科技都
interrupted um mass transportation cars
干扰了我们与人交往的能力，比如公共交通、汽车、
you know uh Tech uh social media all of
科技、社交媒体等等。
these things they've interrupted our
它们干扰了我们
ability to make friends proper friends
结交真正朋友的能力，那种
where you can look each other in the eye
可以面对面交流的友谊。你
you and I could do this over Zoom it
我可以通过Zoom视频通话，但
wouldn't feel the
感觉肯定不
same but you the macro so the remote
一样。从宏观角度来看，远程
work culture the rise in as you say
办公文化，以及
screens and phones
屏幕和手机的兴起，都在减少
optimizing interaction out of our Lives
我们生活中的互动。
I mean like you know if you think about
想想
social networking or Uber Eats or I
社交网络、Uber Eats或者
deliveroo um you you're living your life
Deliveroo之类的外卖平台，你
behind a screen in White Walls now and
现在的生活就像是在白色墙壁的屏幕后面度过的，
it's it feels like it's becoming harder
感觉
and harder and harder to make friends
结交朋友越来越难，找到另一半也越来越难。
make friends in fact what's the
事实上，结交朋友究竟是什么？
interesting thing is sometimes when I
有趣的是，有时候我一下台，总会有一些
young men come up to me and they'll get
年轻小伙子走过来，凑到我跟前，几乎贴到
right up in my personal space and I go
我身上，我心想
this is strange and then they'll say
这有点奇怪。然后他们会问
something to me like um how do I make
我一些问题，比如“我该怎么交
friends and they and I I respect them so
朋友？”。我很敬佩他们能说出这些问题，
much for saying it because I can see how
因为我能看出
difficult it is for them to utter that
对他们来说，说出
those words and I reflect on I was doing
这些话有多难。我回想起之前在
something at Canary Warf and a kid in
金丝雀码头演出的时候，
the front row in a crowd of 500 people
前排有个年轻人，周围500个观众都
they're all wearing suits because
穿着西装，因为
they're working in the corporate world
他们都在企业界工作。
he's surrounded by 500 of his peers his
他被500个和他
age in the front row past the microphone
同龄的人包围着，坐在麦克风前排，却
his question to me on stage is how do I
问我“我该怎么
make friends yeah and there's 499 people
交朋友？”。是啊，
sat next to him that are his age yep and
他旁边坐着499个和他同龄的人，
he's asking in the front row how do I
他却在前排问“我该怎么
make friends and I it was it's so moving
交朋友？”。这真的太让人感动了，
because you know looking looking down on
因为你知道，我俯视着他，
that individual surrounded by people I'm
周围都是人，我心想，你这
like well you know you the brain the
头脑
simple brain goes well just turn to the
简单的人，会想“那就跟
person next you introduce yourself but
旁边的人打个招呼，自我介绍一下啊”。
clearly that was
那
not not the answer because if it was so
不是答案，因为如果事情这么
simple he would just do that and you
简单，他早就…… 就那样做吧。你
said something interesting as well which
还说了些很有意思的话，
I think maybe overlays with that which
我觉得可能跟这个有点关系，那就是
is that we've kind of like lost the art
我们好像失去了
or the skill of making friends y what
交朋友的艺术或技巧。
would you have said to that kid so I'll
你会对那个孩子说什么呢？我给
tell you by way of a story how I would
你讲个故事，说说我会怎么
answer that so A friend of mine was uh
回答这个问题。我有个朋友当时很
struggling uh her career it wasn't going
挣扎，她的事业
as well as she' wanted and her marriage
不如预期，婚姻也出了问题。
was in a bad place in other words when
换句话说，真是祸不单行，
a break right and she was in a really
她一直走运，处境非常
bad place and so she knows what I do for
糟糕。她知道我是做什么的，
a living so she said she asked me can
所以她问我能不能
you help can I come and talk to you and
帮帮她，能不能来找我聊聊，听听我的建议。
get some advice and I said of course
我说当然可以。于是我们每周
and so we had a standing Wednesday
三固定见面，每次见面
every Wednesday for 90 minutes and she
90分钟。她
would tell me what was going on in her
会跟我说说她
life I gave her some advice she felt
生活中的种种，我会给她一些建议。
amazing when she left me it lasted about
她每次离开我的时候都感觉好多了，但这种感觉只持续了
two days and then she'd go back into her
两天，然后她又会陷入
slump and then we get together the next
低谷。到了下个周三我们再见面，
Wednesday she'd feel amazing for about
她又会感觉好多了，大概持续
two days and she'd go back into her
两天，然后又会回到低谷。
slump and this went on for months this
低谷期持续了好几个月，这
was our pattern right so I thought I was
就是我们的模式，对吧？所以我以为自己
doing good work and then it then I just
做得不错，然后就一直
rinse and repeat
重复着同样的模式。
right then I remembered my own work and
后来我想起了我自己的工作，也
I remembered Alcoholics Anonymous which
想起了匿名戒酒会，那是
is the final step the 12th step is
最后一步，第十二步是
service helping somebody who's
服务，帮助那些和
struggling with the problem you're
你一样正在与问题作斗争的人，这才是
actually help you overcome your problem
真正帮助你克服问题的方法。
so I I have struggles I have needs I
我也有挣扎，我有需求，我也
have um uh insecurities and I don't have
有不安全感，而且我没有一个可以
a safe Outlet to talk to so I she's one
安全倾诉的渠道。她是我
of my closest friends in the world I
在这个世界上最亲密的朋友之一，我
trust her implicitly so I said to her
完全信任她。所以我问她，
can I need the coaching as well can we
我是否也需要辅导？我们能不能
split our time 45 minutes for me 45
平分时间，我45分钟，
minutes for you she agreed and it was I
你45分钟？她同意了。
was I knew what I was doing right there
我知道自己在做什么，对吧？这其实是一个
was kind of an experiment happening
实验，
which I didn't let on which is I wanted
我没有让她知道，我想让
her to help me as a way of helping
她帮助我，也是为了帮助她
herself and so what end up happening was
自己。结果，时间不再是
it did ceased to be 4545 I we got
45分钟，我们聚
together and for 90 minutes we talked
在一起，聊了90分钟
about me and then the next Wednesday we
关于我的事情。然后，到了下一个星期三。 我们
got together and for 90 minutes we
聚在一起聊了90分钟，
talked about me and then we got together
聊的都是关于我的事。
and within about three or four weeks her
大约三四个星期后，她的
life was full on back on track
生活就完全恢复了正轨，彻底恢复了。
fully back on track because when you
因为当你
help someone with a thing that you're
帮助别人解决自己正在
struggling with you actually end up
努力的事情时，实际上你也
solving your own problems and so what I
解决了自己的问题。所以我想
would say to that kid is find somebody
对那个孩子说的是，去找一个正在
who's struggling to make a friend and
努力交朋友的人，
help them make a friend make it an act
帮助他们交朋友，把这当成一种
of service because fundamentally if we
服务他人的行为。因为从根本上讲，如果我们深入
dig down deep the the true skill that
挖掘，就会发现
we've lost is service we've
我们真正失去的技能是服务。
overemphasized taking over giving we've
我们过分强调索取而忽略付出，过分强调
overemphasized selfish over selfless
自私而忽略
selfish is important taking is important
无私。自私固然重要，
but not at the expense of giving um and
但不能以牺牲付出为代价，也
not the expense of serving right we've
不能以牺牲服务为代价。
lost we're out of balance and I think we
我们失去了平衡，我认为我们
we've lost the ability to serve Society
失去了服务社会的能力，
we've lost the ability to serve each
失去了彼此服务的能力。
other um you know the Prime Minister
你知道，首相
cores for national service and literally
呼吁国民服务，结果
the whole country erupts and says are
全国上下都炸开了锅，质问他是
you trying not to get reelected you know
不是想让自己落选。
um what did you think of that I thought
你觉得怎么样？我觉得
it was brilliant I do believe in in in
这太棒了。 我确实相信
service it doesn't have to be military
服务，它不一定是兵役。
service you know when we say national
你知道，我们说的国民
service go be a teacher in the inner
服务，是指去城市贫民区当一年老师，或者
month in a
每个月去
hospital go work for one weekend one day
医院工作一天，或者
per month in a in in hospice and pal of
每个月抽出一个周末去临终关怀中心或
care right serve other human beings who
护理机构工作一天，去服务那些被
are underserved or forgotten serve your
忽视或遗忘的人，
nation in some way sh per put you know
以某种方式为国家服务。
let the government give you a list of 20
政府会列出二三
or 30 options of things you can do
十项你可以做的事情，
um and say that if you do these things
并告诉你，如果你做了这些事，
it makes you eligible for you know
你就有资格获得
scholarships it makes you eligible for
奖学金，获得
whatever you know um I'm a great
各种资助。我
believer just like you can get at least
坚信这一点，就像
in the United States very very generous
在美国，
packages for Education if you serve in
如果你服兵役，就能获得非常丰厚的教育资助；如果你从事其他任何服务，比如教书，也能获得
the military give very generous packages
非常丰厚的教育资助。
have problems you know we we we're
你知道，我们现在面临
losing teachers okay well we can fill
教师短缺的问题，我们可以填补
those gaps why why is do you think that
这些空缺。为什么呢？你认为这会在
coming years if we because I think skill
未来几年帮助我们整个社会吗？因为我认为
that the skills that people learn when
人们在
they serve a they learn hard
服务中学到的技能…… 虽然很辛苦，
work but they learn to be a part of
但他们学会了成为
something larger than themselves and you
比自身更伟大的事物的一部分。你去
talk to anybody who goes off and does um
问问那些去做
volunteer work or takes a gap year where
志愿者工作、或者休学一年
they go and do service or anyone who's
去服务的人，或者那些
gone to combat right and you talk to if
上过战场的人，对吧？你去问问那些经历过那些
who who've been in the [__] none of them
糟糕战斗的士兵或海军陆战队员，他们中没有一个人想去
want to go to combat it's not fun
战斗，那可不好玩。与
there's very very very few combat
战斗
related suicides in other words suicides
相关的自杀事件非常非常少，换句话说，自杀
don't happen in a combat situation they
不会发生在战斗中，而是
come they happen when they come back
发生在他们回家之后。
home right um and they all weirdly have
奇怪的是，他们都
warm feelings about their time in combat
对自己的战斗经历怀有一种温暖的情感，这并非源于
and it's not the shooting and the fear
枪林弹雨和恐惧，而是源于那种
it's the intense responsibility and
强烈的责任感和
awesome feeling to be there to look
令人敬畏的感觉——彼此守望相助，
after each other not just to feel looked
不仅仅是被
after but to look after another I talked
照顾，而是真正地去照顾他人。我和
to Navy Seals I talked to Seal Team 6
海豹突击队队员聊过，我和海豹突击队第六分队聊过，
and I wanted to understand the why of
我想了解
the SEAL Teams these this is one of the
海豹突击队存在的意义。这是地球上
highest performing organizations on the
最优秀的部队之一，对吧？
planet right and you think it's going to
你可能会认为它只是关于
be about Brawn and courage and all the
蛮力、勇气以及外界对
thinks that the Commandos and the
突击队员和
special operators have it's actually not
特种作战人员的种种愚蠢看法。 其实根本不是这样，
that at all which is they care for each
他们彼此之间的关爱
other more than others think possible
远超常人想象，
it's their love of each other that makes
正是这份爱让
them special operators and their courage
他们成为特种作战人员，他们的勇气
doesn't come from raw courage I've asked
并非源于赤裸裸的胆量。我问过
many I've talked to many many many seals
很多海豹突击队员和特种作战人员，我跟很多很多海豹突击队员
and special operators about this they
和特种作战人员谈过这个问题，
they don't have just raw courage to run
他们并非只有冲锋陷阵的勇气，而是
that they fear letting down their
害怕辜负
comrades more than
战友胜过害怕
dying and we saw it happen recently
死亡。我们最近就目睹了这样一件事：在一次海豹
where a seal mission one of the seals
突击队任务中，一名海豹
fell into the water and another seal
落水，另一名海豹跳入水中
dived in to catch him and they both died
救他，结果两人都牺牲了。他们害怕辜负
other down more than dying that that
彼此胜过害怕死亡，这种感觉
cannot be described anything else
无法用其他任何词语来形容，
feeling than
除了爱，没有其他词语能够捕捉到这种感觉。这是一种
us will ever understand and that love is
我们大多数人永远无法理解的爱，这种爱
so deep that a lot of them have failed
如此深沉，以至于很多海豹突击队员的
marriages because when their wives say
婚姻都以失败告终。因为当他们的妻子
to them it's either me or the or your
对他们说“要么选我，要么选你的
fellow seals they choose their fellow
战友”时，他们总是选择战友。这就是
love that's love and even my even in my
爱，这就是爱。即使在我们这样的
world like you and I you and I have
世界里，你我之间也有
colleagues and co-workers in the
同事和伙伴，
military they have brothers and sisters
军人之间有兄弟姐妹，
those relationships are real and I
这种关系是真真切切的。我
remember the first time A friend of mine
记得第一次，一个穿
in uniform called me brother on the
制服的朋友在电话里叫我“兄弟”，
phone and he said Hey brother was the
他说：“嘿，兄弟。”这是他
first time he called me brother and I
第一次这么叫我，我当时就
felt it that that you don't use that
觉得，这个
term loosely it's not a it's not just a
词不能随便用，它不是那种
generic term of endearment you earn to
泛泛的爱称，
be called brother or
兄弟
sister and I I remember when he called
姐妹的称呼是需要赢得的。我记得他叫
me brother that it meant something and
我“兄弟”的时候，我知道这意义非凡。
this guy this guy this friend of mine
这个人，我的这个朋友，
he's still active Judy he's a combat
他现在还在服役，他是个战斗
hero he's risked his life he's put
英雄，他冒着生命危险，他把
himself in harm way he's saved the lives
自己置于危险之中，他救过
of people he's an absolute Warrior right
别人的命，他是个真正的战士，对吧？
he's a he is by any definition a
他无论从哪个角度来说，都是个
freaking badass [__] Warrior right
了不起的战士。
and he was the first
他是第一个对
man who said to me I love you we got off
我说“我爱你”的人。我们挂断
the phone he goes we just saying goodbye
电话后，他只是在互相道别，我们聊了
to each other we had a nice long
很久。到了
conversation we got up there and he goes
那里，他说：“我爱你。”
I love you he didn't say love you
他没有说“爱你”，他
he didn't say love you he said I love
没有说“爱你”，他说的是“我爱
you that's real and we we hedge because
你”，这是真情实感。我们当时都觉得很惊讶。
we're afraid of our emotions we're
我们害怕自己的情绪，
afraid of expressing ourselves to each
害怕向彼此表达自己。
other we say things like that we say
我们说“我
love you even love you say those three
爱你”，甚至对别人说出这三个字都无比
excruciatingly excruciatingly difficult
艰难，
unless you actually mean it I love you
除非你是真心实意的。“我爱你”这句话的力量如此
and it was so powerful that now every
强大，以至于现在
time he and I talk and we talk politics
每次我和他聊天，我们聊政治，
and we talk Global stuff and we talk
聊全球事务，聊
leadership we have you know and then at
领导力，你知道的，在
the end of our calls I'll say I'll talk
通话结束时，我会说“我
to you real soon I love you he goes I
很快再聊，我爱你”，他会说“我
love you too that's how we end our phone
也爱你”，这就是我们结束通话的方式。
calls and I started experimenting I
我开始尝试，我
started saying those words to the
开始对
especially the men in my life that I
生命中那些我
love and care about desperately my male
深爱和关心的男人们说这句话，尤其是我的男性
friends it's easier to say to a woman is
朋友。对女人说这句话更容易些，因为对女人来说，这
there's less of a stigma right
没什么污名，对吧？有些
and guys who are guy some of my guy
男人，比如我的一些男性
friends who are if you met them you
朋友，如果你见到他们，你
would describe them as not very warm you
会觉得他们不太热情，你
would describe them as distant or cold
会觉得他们疏远、冷漠
or guarded and they
或戒备，嗯……我
remember taking the risk saying to them
记得我冒着风险对他们说，
when we got off the phone or when I said
当我们挂断电话，或者我和他们
goodbye to them when I was hanging out
告别，或者我和
with them I said I love
他们一起出去玩的时候，我会说： 我爱
you
你，
and and in in not in very short order
没过多久，
they started saying it
他们就开始回应我，
back and we would hug
我们拥抱的方式也变了，
differently and we would kiss each other
我们会亲吻彼此的
cheek you know and like one of my
脸颊。你知道，就像我的一个
friends who he's a cold guy he's not
朋友，他性格比较冷淡，他并不
he's not warm he's lovely and smart and
热情，他很可爱、聪明、了不起、
fantastic and funny but he's not
风趣，但他就是不
warm it took him a long time and I
热情。我跟他
always said it him I love you I love you
说了很久“我爱你，我爱你”，他总是说“
and he he goes yeaha okay
嗯，好的”，
and I would like hug him and kiss him
然后我会拥抱他，亲吻他的
with the cheek goodbye he's like okay
脸颊道别，他会说“好的”，
and then he started saying I love you
然后他就开始回应“我爱你”。
and this is what I've learned from the
这就是我从
highest performing teams on the planet
全球最优秀的团队身上学到的，也是
this is what I've learned from people
我从那些懂得服务的人身上学到的：
service without developing some sort of
没有
love and so I think I think to go all
爱，就没有服务。所以，我想回到
kid in the front row how do I make
前排那个孩子的问题——“我该如何交
friends you can't make a friend until
朋友？”——答案是：在
you learn how to serve because
你学会服务之前，你无法交到朋友，因为
friendship is fundamentally service
友谊的本质是服务，
friendship is an act of service and if
友谊是一种服务行为。如果
you don't know the skill of service then
你不懂得服务的技巧，
you probably don't know how to be a
你可能就不知道如何成为
friend let alone make a friend I think
朋友，更别说交朋友了。 我认为
you have to learn to be a friend before
你必须先学会如何做朋友才能
you can make a friend because only
交到朋友，因为只有当
you know how to be their friend right
你懂得如何做朋友时，别人才会愿意和你做朋友。这和一起玩乐不一样，和跟
your mates that's
哥们儿出去喝得烂醉也不一样，那些才是真正的乐趣，
fun those are m
那些是
are those friends that you love maybe
你真心喜欢的朋友。
sometimes sometimes those overlap that's
有时候，这两者之间会有交集，这也是个
the other problem and I I live in
问题。我住在
America where you meet somebody once and
美国，在这里你只要见过一个人，
they call you friend and the problem is
他们就会称你为朋友。问题是，
I think we overuse the word friend right
我觉得我们滥用了“朋友”这个词。
like if you have a a mild melanoma and
比如，如果你得了轻度黑色素瘤，同时又
you have staged for liver cancer we call
被诊断出肝癌，我们都会把这
both those things cancer clearly they're
两种情况都称为癌症，显然它们
not the same thing and I think we have
并不相同。我觉得我们
the same problem with the word friend
对“朋友”这个词的使用也存在同样的问题。
like somebody you hang out with casually
比如，和一些平时一起出去玩、开怀
it's it's a laugh you know we call that
大笑的人，我们会称他们为
person friend but then somebody who we
朋友；但对于那些我们
have deep love for and we would be there
深爱、无论如何都会支持的人，我们也会
for them no matter what we call that
称他们为朋友，甚至“
person friend best friend doesn't seem
最好的朋友”都无法完全
to capture it either and so I think we
表达那种感觉。所以我觉得我们
need more words like I've started using
需要更多不同的词，比如我开始
the word acquaintance I've started using
用“熟人”、“
the word work friend uh or deal friend
同事”或者“交易伙伴”来形容。
that's like in finance right I like them
这就像在金融界一样，对吧？我喜欢他们，
I get along with them I enjoy them I but
我和他们相处融洽，我很享受和他们在一起的时光。但
if we weren't working if we weren't if
如果我们不在公司合作，如果我们不合作，如果
our companies weren't working together
我们的公司不合作，我还会像以前那样经常
would I hang out with them as much
和他们一起玩吗？
probably not I probably would make less
可能不会，我可能会减少一些
of an effort right
精力。
are you are you religious I believe in
你信教吗？我相信
belief what does I believe in the
信仰。我相信
importance of believing in something and
信仰的重要性。
so for those who choose Faith
所以对于那些选择信仰——
traditional Faith as the thing to
传统信仰——作为
believe in and offer guidance I think
信仰对象和指引的人来说，我认为这
that's good um for people who find cause
很好。对于那些寻找事业的人来说，
whether it's social cause um or some
无论是社会事业还是
type of other cause to feel a part of I
其他类型的事业，让他们感到自己是其中的一份子，
I think I think it is essential that we
我认为这至关重要。
believe in something I I believe in
我相信
belief it's funny cuz all the the
信仰。有趣的是，你刚才提到的所有
about community and other subjects that
关于社区和其他与
kind of intersect with that service and
服务和
purpose these all came inherent within
目标相关的议题，都源于
religion yeah religion gave us all of
宗教。是的，宗教曾经给了我们所有
these once upon a time now in the
这些。现在，在
absence of religion like and the rise in
宗教衰落和
digitalization we're struggling to find
数字化兴起的背景下，我们正在努力寻找
those things and we're trying to make
这些东西，并试图创造
them like it's such a good question
它们。这是一个很好的问题，对吧？
right which is religion provided a code
宗教提供了一种准则，可以
arguably a code that you so let let so
说是一种准则。 举个
here's the example right so
例子，维多利亚时代有
victorians there were some incredibly
很多极其
wealthy victorians who gave tremendous
富有的人，他们将巨额
amounts of their wealth wealth back to
财富回馈
society they established Charities they
社会。他们设立慈善机构，
built hospitals in fact many of the
建造医院，事实上，
institutions that exist today were
如今许多机构都是
established by wealthy victorians the
由维多利亚时代的富人建立的。
same is true in the United States the
美国的情况也是如此，比如卡内基家族
carnegies and the Rockefellers right and
和洛克菲勒家族。我
looked at the tax code from the Carnegie
查阅了卡内基
and Rockefeller days or the George
和洛克菲勒时代，以及乔治·
Eastman days and I went and looked up
伊士曼时代的税法，也查阅了
the tax code in the UK as well and there
英国的税法。当时的税法
was no sophisticated tax code in other
并不完善，也就是说，
rebate or deduction for giving to
捐赠
charity zero zero there was no tax
慈善机构没有任何退税、折扣或税收减免。无论是
benefit in the UK or the US for giving
在英国还是美国，捐赠
to charity and in the conversations with
慈善机构都没有任何税收优惠。在与
the carnegies The Rockefellers and some
卡内基家族、洛克菲勒家族以及一些
of the wealthy victorians they all said
维多利亚时代的富人的交谈中，他们都表示，
that they believe that they had a quote
他们认为自己有“
unquote moral obligation to give back to
道德义务”回馈
society and it was born out of religion
社会，这无疑源于宗教信仰。他们
without a doubt they were God-fearing
敬畏上帝，这一点毋庸置疑。 人们有
in moral obligations to return their
道德义务归还
wealth and give something back to
财富，回馈
societies establishing universities
社会，建立大学、
hospitals and the rest of it right now
医院等等。但现在看来，
it seems that people give charity if
人们似乎只有在
they can get a tax benefit from it and
能获得税收优惠的情况下才会捐赠慈善。
the question is is where is the moral
问题是，这种道德
obligation coming from and so when we
义务从何而来？所以，当我们
talk about the fact that people are less
谈到
religious today but you I think your
如今人们的宗教信仰有所淡漠时，我认为你的
your assertion is correct people are are
说法是正确的，人们正在
abandoning the traditional church
放弃传统的教会，教会
membership is down and I would argue
成员人数下降。我认为这是
that uh because the churches have lost
因为教会失去了
relevance right like take the Catholic
相关性。就拿天主教会来说，如果
church for example like you're trying to
你试图
appeal to Young People by wearing 400y
通过穿着400
old clothes and speaking in
年前的服装，用
Latin maybe we genes and speak English
拉丁语（或许是英语）
or whatever the local language is like
或其他当地语言来吸引年轻人，那么
if you want to be quote unquote relevant
如果你想“与时俱进”，
you're not changing the faith abandoning
你并没有改变信仰，也没有放弃
the faith you're not you're not
信仰。
Blasphemous by changing the the the what
改变
you're wearing and and and and the
你的穿着和
language you're speaking in you're still
语言并不亵渎神明，你仍然在
preaching the faith but you'll find
宣扬信仰，但你会发现
yourself more attractive I had the
自己更有吸引力。我曾经有
opportunity to go to Kanye Sunday
机会参加坎耶·韦斯特的周日
service back when it was okay to do
礼拜，那时
anything with Kanye um uh I just was
和坎耶·韦斯特在一起还很正常，嗯，我只是
invited as a as as I was a friend of a
受邀而已。 因为我是朋友的朋友，所以
friend and I went to the Sunday service
我去参加了周日礼拜。
religious or not that was a religious
不管你信不信教，那都是一次宗教
experience did you ever go I did yeah it
体验。你去过吗？我去过。是的，真是
is it's unbelievable yeah and and you
难以置信。而且，你
could and and for those when I say for
可以去。我说的是
those who haven't gone like anybody
那些还没去过的人，其实任何人都
could go you just to get on the signup
可以去，只要在报名
sheet like you could just sign anyone
表上签名就行了，任何人都
could go was open to the general public
可以去，对公众开放，但
it just sold out quick I mean it was
很快就报满了。我的意思是，虽然是
free but the the list filled up quickly
免费的，但名单很快就满了。
um and uh basically what happened is
嗯，基本上，当时的情况是，
there's a there's a band a choir in the
中间有一个乐队和一个唱诗班，
middle and the parishioners sat all the
教友们围坐在
way in a circle around the outside you
外围。你
sat
坐在
there your body was consumed by song and
那里，你的身体完全沉浸在歌声和
music
音乐中。
and it was and you know there's like
你知道，在
Sufi tradition where
苏菲派传统中，
music becomes the thing the way you the
音乐成为你
way you find spirituality the way you
寻找灵性、
find meditation or like the whirling
冥想的方式，就像旋转
dervishes who spin around in the music
舞者在音乐中旋转一样。
and the and it's the repetition and it
这是一种重复。
was sitting in this beautiful place
坐在这个美丽的地方，
consumed by songs that went on for 10
沉浸在持续不断的歌声中……
minutes each that you found spirituality
每人十分钟，
whether you had traditional religion you
无论你生活中是否有传统宗教信仰，你都能找到精神寄托。
and um there was community and I I for
嗯，那里有社群。我和
one went with a friend and uh I think
朋友一起去的。嗯，我觉得
that's what traditional Church doesn't
传统教会没有
realize which is you can modernize old
意识到的是，你可以让古老的
beliefs and if you do that you will find
信仰现代化。如果你这样做，你会发现它
relevance amongst young people um but
与年轻人息息相关。嗯，
young people are looking for something
年轻人正在寻找一些东西。
there's something called Hillsong which
有个叫Hillsong的教会，
is an American church but it's the joke
是美国的一个教会，但人们常开玩笑说，那里就像是俊男
is it's like where all the pretty people
靓女的聚集地。嗯，它很年轻，也很贴近生活。
relevant and like the pastor has like
牧师留着
got a beard and an earring and you know
胡子，戴着耳环，穿着
jeans and you know duck Mars and there's
牛仔裤，你知道，还有Duck Mars乐队。
a rock band and but they preach the
他们也宣扬
gospel and it has and it fills up entire
福音，而且他们的聚会总是爆满。
Arenas um so people are looking to
嗯，人们渴望
belong to something and they're looking
归属感，渴望
to believe in something and they're
信仰，渴望被
looking to be led and they're looking
引领，渴望
for community and they're looking for um
社群，渴望
um codes of conduct and values that they
行为准则和价值观，渴望
can that they can um uh keep alive in
在
their own lives and their own traditions
自己的生活中传承下去。 他们拥有自己的传统，
and um there are precious few of those
而这样的
places left which is why I think people
地方现在所剩无几，所以我认为人们
are desperately looking for them and
才会如此迫切地寻找它们，并
latching onto kind of the first thing
抓住第一个
that shows up I think it's one of the
出现的机会。我认为这也是
biggest business opportunities of our
我们这个时代最大的商业机会之一。
time as well I say this at multiple
我从多个
levels I'm talking about if I'm an
层面来说，如果我是一个正在考虑在
entrepreneur thinking about where to
哪里创业的企业家，或者
start a business but also if I'm an
如果我是一个正在
entrepreneur and I'm thinking about how
思考如何
to run my company and my culture I it's
运营公司和打造企业文化的企业家，这都非常重要。
funny this I've got one particular
有趣的是，我有一个
opinion that went out of fashion and now
观点曾经过时，但在
the pandemic which is I always believed
疫情期间又重新流行起来，那就是我一直坚信应该
in doing things in person and having
面对面地做事，让
people together even this podcast never
人们聚在一起。即使是这个播客，也从未用过
did it over Zoom even through the
Zoom。即使在
pandemic we just two meter distance and
疫情期间，我们也保持两米的距离。
get if someone couldn't come in and we
如果有人不能来，我们也
weren't going to release I just didn't
不会发布节目，我只是不想这么做，
want to because it's what's the point
因为那样就失去了意义，对吧？就
right but also in terms of company
企业
culture I think companies now that offer
文化而言，我认为现在很多公司都提供……
I'm in so many interviews I don't think
我参加过很多面试，我想
people would believe I'm in so many
人们不会相信，我参加过很多
interviews where the candidate asks me
面试，候选人都会让我
to check that they're going to going I
确认…… 他们要走了。我
was in one yesterday with the young
昨天和一位
25-year-old lady um she asked she
25岁的年轻女士聊过，她特意
checked that people were going to come
确认大家是否会来
in the office and be together it was
办公室一起工作。感觉她好像除非
job unless we off we were a community we
我们能像一个社区一样，否则她根本不会接受这份工作。
she was talking about run clubs she was
她谈到跑步俱乐部，谈到
talking about reform of plates she was
餐盘改革，谈到她
talking about that she likes to do
喜欢
climbing walls and she wanted to check
攀岩，她想确认
that we we were in the office together
我们是否能一起在办公室工作。
and I think you know good for her you
我觉得她做得对，你
know what I mean but like the the the
明白我的意思。但是，
narrative through the pandemic
疫情期间，
especially led by the west coast of
尤其是
America was that remote forever and um
美国西海岸，一直流传着“远程办公将永远持续下去”之类的说法。
you know all that kind of thing but it's
但
I've always believed that the
我一直相信，
fundamental needs of human being will
人类的基本需求
mean that connection and being together
意味着人与人之间的联系和团聚终将到来。是的，
will be will prevail yeah I I agree with
我同意这一点。
that but but but how much damage has to
但是，我们究竟要付出多大的代价才能
be done until we get there you know and
实现这一点呢？
I think we have a responsibility to help
我认为我们有责任帮助
people like to to bring people together
人们，让人们聚在一起。
the states at least is young people
至少在美国，我看到的一个趋势是，年轻人，
especially those who started their
特别是那些
careers in the pandemic or slightly
在疫情期间或疫情前不久开始职业生涯的人，他们有点…… 我
love with the whole room the Romance of
爱上了整个房间，爱上了
the you know remote work thing
远程办公的浪漫，你知道，很多人都在
um are struggling a lot of them are
挣扎，很多人都在
struggling with mental health challenges
经历心理健康和
with mental fitness challenges and when
心理素质方面的挑战。当
they're forced to come into work which
他们被迫回到工作岗位时——
is actually an antidote once they get
实际上，工作岗位是一种解药——
there they freak out and they think that
他们反而会崩溃，认为
it's the the workspace that's making it
工作环境让他们
more stressful but it's not it's that
压力更大，但事实并非如此。真正的原因是，
you've been at home and alone so much
你在家独处了太久，
come back in you know it's like it's
回到工作岗位就像是对身体的一次冲击。你知道，这就像
like when you're out of shape and you go
你身材走样，去
to the gym it really hurts you have to
健身房锻炼会很痛苦，但你必须
stick with it you know um it's like when
坚持下去。就像
you get off drugs and you go through
你戒毒后经历
withdrawal you makes you want to go back
戒断反应，会让你想要重新
to the drug right and so my fear is that
吸毒一样。所以我担心的是，真正
thing that's making me mentally unfit
让我心理健康状况恶化的，是待在家里的远程办公环境，
and it's not the coming back into work
而不是回到工作岗位本身。
even though it hurts and it's a shock
即使回到工作岗位会很痛苦，会让我感到震惊，我会逃避，但我
I have to I have to stick with it I have
必须坚持下去。 我
to going to the gym I have to stay off
必须去健身房。
the juice like you know um do you think
你知道，为了避免过度依赖果汁，嗯，你觉得
this is in part because the office is
这部分原因是不是因为办公室过时了？办公室的
designed like you know multiple decades
设计理念是几十年前的，
ago and the needs of the human being in
而
the modern world if we're saying it's
现代社会的人们的需求却与此背道而驰。如果我们说
like the office itself should be
办公室更注重人与人之间的联系和社群，那么办公室本身就应该
redesigned it should be it should serve
重新设计，它应该更像是
more as a community like Center I mean
一个社群中心，而
versus just a place to the office has
不仅仅是一个办公场所。办公室已经随着
times I mean it used to be you know the
时代变迁而多次改变。以前，
executives had the corner offices with
高管们拥有带窗户的角落办公室，
Windows and the rest of us had you know
而我们其他人则只能在
cubes in the middle and then at some
中间的隔间里办公。后来，
point we started giving the nice offices
我们开始把漂亮的办公室分配给
to the to younger people on the outside
年轻人，把
and then we made the outside offices the
外面的办公室改成
conference rooms and then we went to
会议室，然后又变成了
open plan I mean like the offices have
开放式办公。我的意思是，办公室
taken multiple different cultural
经历了多次不同的文化
changes rightfully so the office should
变革，这是理所当然的。所以，办公室应该
reflect the times you're right you know
与时俱进。你说得对。
one of my favorite ones is if you visit
我最喜欢的例子之一是
the Pixar
皮克斯的
offices the way Steve Jobs helped design
办公室。史蒂夫·乔布斯参与设计的
the Pixar office is they put the
皮克斯办公室，他们把卫生间放在了
bathrooms in the middle middle as most
中间，而
most officers have the bathrooms on the
大多数办公室的卫生间都在外面。
the middle so no matter where you worked
所以，无论你在哪里工作，
you had to walk past other people to go
你都得经过其他人才能去
to the L and at some point dur the day
L区。而且一天中某个时候，
everyone has to go to the L MH and so
每个人都必须去L区（MH），这是故意设计的，为了
that was done on purpose to force you to
迫使大家
interact and and have
互动，创造一些
Serendipity um but little things like
意外的惊喜。嗯，就是像
that um communal eading I'm a huge fan
这样的小事，比如集体用餐。我非常喜欢
of communal eating I'm a huge fan of
集体用餐，非常喜欢那种“
like let's go let's let's eat together
走吧，一起吃饭吧”的感觉。
um uh you know I built my office to feel
你知道，我把我的办公室布置得
like a living room there's like
像个客厅，里面有
different living room areas you can sit
不同的客厅区域，你可以坐在
up here you can sit over there but it's
这里，也可以坐在那里，但都是
just couches and people sit wherever
沙发，大家可以随意选择座位。每个
they want and you know people have their
人都有自己的“
quote unquote their desk you know where
办公桌”，也就是
they like to sit and there's back rooms
他们喜欢坐的地方。
if you need to make calls but it's all
如果你需要打电话，后面还有房间。但所有地方都是
just couches it's all super comfy it
沙发，非常舒适，
feels like it feels like a home if
感觉就像家一样。如果
people want to work at home great here's
有人想在家工作，太好了，这里就是
a home literally you walk into my office
一个家。你走进我的办公室，
I mean you've been there it's a home
我的意思是，你来过这里，它就像一个家，一个
it's a home yeah it's it's a home and uh
家。 这里就像家一样，
cuz I want people to have have that home
因为我希望人们能有家的
experience we've got a fridge and a
感觉，所以我们有冰箱和
kitchen and you can you know I can
厨房。我知道，
imagine the rebuttal to a lot of people
很多正在
that are listening to us where they
听我们说话的人可能会反驳说，他们每天要花
genuinely they have an hour commute to
一个小时通勤，然后
go into some horrible little cubicle
挤进一个可怕的小隔间，
surround they have to wear a suit they
还得穿西装，
get no Freedom so my bias is that
没有任何自由。当然，我的立场是，
obviously I'm the CEO of the company so
我是这家公司的CEO，所以
I have you know these freedoms and our
我享有这些自由，而且我们的企业
our culture is much more relaxed and
文化也更加轻松
free but there's a lot of people that
自由。但是，很多人对
their relationship with work is it's
工作的态度很
awful it's like an awful place to be
糟糕，工作就像一个可怕的地方。是的，
yeah and I think so the question is
我认为这个问题问得
great okay so instead of rejecting it
很好。那么，与其否定它，
how would you redesign it to make you
你会如何重新设计，才能让人们
want to come in okay you don't want to
愿意来上班呢？比如，你不想
wear a suit don't wear a suit maybe you
穿西装，那就不用穿西装。也许只有在
meeting with a client that seems if if
和客户开会的时候才需要穿西装，如果
you're in that kind of business yeah you
你从事的是那种类型的业务的话。是的，你
know I live in Los Angeles where
知道，我住在洛杉矶，那里
everybody dress likes everybody dresses
每个人都穿
like 16y olds but you know that seems
得像16岁的孩子，但你知道，这似乎很
fair wear a suit only when you're
公平。 只有在
meeting with a client if that if your
会见客户时才穿西装，如果你的
business requires that um otherwise
业务需要的话。否则，
where whatever um you know so and so
你知道的，等等。总之，
again it goes back to service which is I
这又回到了服务上来。我
think that people have to earn the right
认为人们必须先赢得
to complain right and you earn the right
抱怨的权利，对吧？赢得
to complain by in some small way to fix
抱怨的权利的方式就是以某种方式
the problem yourself not exhausting
自己解决问题，而不是穷尽
every possibility like you're not
所有可能性。比如，
unless you've at least voted right you
除非你至少投过票，否则你不能抱怨政治。对吧？你
don't have to have joined a movement you
不需要加入任何运动，也不需要参与
don't have to have campaigned just the
竞选活动，只要做到
minimum the minimum then you can
最低限度，你就可以
complain about anything you like and so
抱怨任何你想抱怨的事情。所以，
if you've tried to fix the office then
如果你尝试过改善办公室，那么
you can complain about the office if you
你就可以抱怨办公室。如果你
just sit at home and whine about
只是坐在家里抱怨，
it like maybe like get involved and
也许应该参与进来，而
don't do it for yourself
不是只为自己。
here's we go back to service don't do it
我们又回到了服务上来。不要
for yourself do it for the other people
为自己，而是为了那些讨厌上班的人，他们每天
commute to sit in a little cubicle and
通勤一个小时，坐在狭小的隔间里，
wear a suit that they don't want to wear
穿着他们不想穿的西装。
do it for the people you love do it for
为了你爱的人，为了
the people you care about do it for the
你关心的人，为了你
person to the left and the person to the
左边的人，为了你右边的人。
right don't do it for yourself you
别为自己做，你这个
selfish bastard right do it for someone
自私的混蛋！对吧？去做吧，为了
else to make their feeling of coming to
别人，让他们
work better how can you make it feel
更乐意来上班。怎样才能让你的
better for somebody else you work with
同事更乐意来
to come to work and that's what we're
上班呢？这就是我们
missing we're all about ourselves and
忽略的地方。我们都只关注自己，
yet we've forgotten email is another one
却忘了电子邮件也是个例子。
you know why you get so many emails cuz
你知道为什么你会收到那么多邮件吗？因为你
you send so many emails stop BC seeing
发送了太多邮件。别再这样了，别再这样了。比如
when somebody says what time is the
有人问
meeting and you reply all and write 3:00
会议几点开始，你就回复所有人，写上“3点”；
or what do you want for lunch and you
或者有人问午饭想吃什么，你就回复“
reply and write chicken please like you
鸡肉，谢谢”。你
made everybody open that email you
让所有人都打开了你的邮件，你这个没
thoughtless bastard right why don't you
脑子的混蛋！对吧？与其担心自己
help everybody else get to inbox zero
收件箱清空，为什么不帮帮别人清空
inbox zero so in other words pick up the
收件箱呢？换句话说，
phone when possible
尽可能打电话。
you know send few emails take people off
少发邮件，把人从
the CC list like I get an email it's got
抄送列表里移除。比如我收到一封邮件，抄送了
five people CC I realize that my reply
五个人，我意识到我的回复其
only really matters to two people and I
实只对两个人有用，所以我
take people off the CC list you know
把他们从抄送列表里移除，
because I want them to have fewer
因为我想让他们少收到
emails because otherwise everybody's
邮件，不然大家都会
hitting you know reply all and then
点击“全部回复”。 大家都
we're all you know suffering from email
知道，我们都遭受着电子邮件
bankruptcy the um anyway acts of service
破产的困扰，嗯，总之，服务行为，
acts of service I mean there's so many
服务行为，我的意思是，有很多小事，很多小事，
things um stupid things stupid things I
嗯，蠢事，蠢事。我当时
was walking down the streets of New York
走在纽约街头，
and a guy was parking his
一个家伙正在停车，
car and uh it happened to be a huge
呃，碰巧那是一个
space big enough for two cars right like
足够停两辆车的大车位，对吧？
and he parked right in the middle and it
他把车停在了正中间，那又
wasn't like it was his brand new cut he
不是他的新车，他好像
was like afraid of getting it bumped
怕被人撞到，或者
turned it just it was just a car right
转弯，它只是一辆车而已，对吧？
and I said to him hey I sort of like
我跟他说，嘿，我轻轻地
tapped on the sort of like wave down his
拍了拍他的
window like I waved like hey just so you
车窗，挥了挥手，就像挥手说，嘿，你
know there's a ton of room behind you or
知道吗，你后面或者
in front of you if you move your car up
前面都有很多空间，如果你把车往前挪
or back you'll make room for another car
或者往后挪，就能腾出地方停另一辆车了。
and he goes there's no room I'm like no
他说，没地方了。我说，
no no no I'm standing out here there's
不不不不，我就站在这儿，
you got like five feet in front of you
你前面还有五英尺的空间，
like there's plenty of room I I'll I'll
空间很充足，
guide you if you want you know I was
如果你需要，我可以帮你。你知道，我当时态度
being super nice about it and he goes I
非常友好，但他还是说，
think it's just fine I'm like no no no
我觉得挺好的，我说不行不行不行
no I like you another car could he goes
不行，我想让你把车挪到别的地方去。
are you trying to park your car he says
他问我：“你在停车吗？”
to me I said no but I I've tried to park
我说没有，但我
in New York before and I know it's hard
以前在纽约停车过，我知道
to find a space so you know maybe it'd
找车位很难，所以你知道，也许你可以把
be nice to pull your car up and let
车挪开，让
another the guy would hear nothing of it
别人停一下。那家伙根本不听，
he turned his car off and got out of the
他熄火
car and walked away and like that's what
下车走开了。这就是我的意思，
I mean you know which is you know here's
你知道，这就是
the advice I wanted to tell him I didn't
我想告诉他的建议。我没说出口，
say this but I wanted to be like hey
但我想说的是，嘿，
just can I offer you an observation you
我能跟你说说吗？你
live in the world like you live in the
生活在这个世界上，
people in the world and I'm not asking
世界上还有其他人。我不是要
you to give up your weekends and work in
你放弃周末去
hospitals I'm not asking you to join the
医院工作，我不是要你参军，
military I'm not asking you to give up
我不是要你放弃
your salary and become a teacher I'm not
工资去当老师，我不是要
asking you to do any of those things I'm
你做这些事。我只是希望
asking you to consider that somebody
你能考虑一下，
else might want to par and it's an act
其他人可能也想停车，挪一下
of service to like move your car to make
车让别人停一下是一种服务。
a little room for somebody who you don't
给陌生人留个空间？
know do you think that individualism
你觉得个人主义
is hurting us on an individual level I
在个人层面上伤害了我们吗？我的
mean is that of course you want to know
意思是，你当然想知道
why we're lonely cuz we've we've
我们为什么孤独，因为我们把
architected Our Lives to be lonely
自己的生活设计得如此孤独，
of course it's hurting us we are social
这当然会伤害我们。我们是社会性
animals who've over indexed un rugged
动物，却过度推崇不加修饰的
individualism with hero wise
个人主义，把那些自以为是的
CEOs like I love you you're great you're
CEO奉为英雄。我爱你，你很棒，你很
wonderful but people consider you a hero
了不起，但人们把你当成英雄，当成
and their business Guru blah blah blah I
他们的商业导师，等等等等。我
know for a fact that you didn't do it
知道你并非
alone I know for a fact that you've got
孤军奋战，我知道你有一个
teams of people who make you look good
团队让你看起来很出色，
what are you talking about I know I know
你在说什么？我知道，我知道有人在你身上
for a fact that people took bets on you
押注，在你身上冒险，我知道
people made introductions for you I knew
有人为你引荐。我知道你一无所有的时候，
when you had nothing sure you had Moxy
你当然有勇气，
sure you had talent but if it weren't
你当然有才华，但如果没有那些
for people who tried supported helped
尝试过、支持过你、帮助
you know opened a door there would be no
你、为你打开机会之门的人，就不会有
Steven Bartlett of course even my
史蒂文·巴特利特。当然，甚至我的
parents the first people I think about
父母，我首先想到的
is my parents I don't know why they
就是我的父母，我不知道他们为什么
cared so much about me I was just I feel
那么关心我。 关于我，我觉得
like you know kids feel they objectively
你知道，孩子们客观上
look like such a
看起来就像个
burden I feel the way you know what I
负担，我也有同感，你知道我的意思吗？
mean I was like why why would you do
我当时就想，为什么？为什么要
that yeah why would my mom and dad care
这么做？是啊，为什么我的父母会
so much about this little bundle of
这么在意这个小小的
cells I don't understand they would just
细胞团？我不明白，他们简直要
like kill themselves to you know but it
崩溃了。
matters but we know parenting matters we
但这件事很重要，我们都知道养育孩子很重要，我们
know parents that build up their kids
知道那些能够培养孩子
confidences uh really really you know
自信的父母，真的，真的，你知道，那些
parents that are capable of building
能够培养
their kids confidence really really
孩子自信的父母，真的非常
matters you know as opposed to telling a
重要。你知道，而不是不断地告诉
kid constantly to do everything wrong
孩子所有的事情都是错的，那样
like that'll hurt the kid for the rest
会伤害孩子一辈子，
of their life and they're going to have
他们需要
to do tremendous amount of work to
付出巨大的努力才能
overcome that you know it's interesting
克服这些伤害。有趣的是，
even on this overlaid with this is the
即便如此，
idea that populations in the western
西方
world are actually declining because by
世界的人口实际上正在下降，因为生育的
having less and less kids we're actually
孩子越来越少，我们实际上
making it more about ourselves we want
更加关注自己，我们想
to work longer we want to achieve our
工作更长时间，我们想实现自己的
career goals and now having kids and
职业目标，现在，生育孩子以及为人
that sort of active service of parenting
父母这种积极的付出
has now become deprioritized and it's a
已经被边缘化了，这
real problem for the Western world
对西方世界来说是一个真正的问题，
because of the you know aging population
因为你知道，人口老龄化。
and very often for selfish reasons like
很多时候，出于自私的原因，比如
I want to live my life 100% yeah um yeah
我想百分百地活出自己的人生，嗯，嗯，嗯，我的
yeah I mean I think to your point I
意思是，我
think we
觉得你说得对，我们已经
have we have forgotten that we're social
忘记了我们是社会
animals I mean like just go back a few
动物。我的意思是，想想几年前，
years a few decades
几十年前，比如二战时期，想想那种战友
um the camaraderie I mean think about
情谊。想想
Britain during the second world war so
二战期间美国和英国发生了什么，想想
during the Blitz the number of people
闪电战期间，有多少人把
who sent their children to the
孩子送到
countryside and they stayed back to
乡下，自己留下来
support the war effort okay they didn't
支援战争。他们没有带着
children they could have they sent their
孩子一起搬到乡下，他们本来可以的，但他们把孩子送去了乡下。想想这有多
think about the insanity of that right
疯狂。
now that parents sent their children to
现在想想，父母把孩子送到
the country to be safe to be raised by
乡下，让他们由
another family with the full expectation
另一个家庭抚养，以确保安全，并且完全相信
that they would that they may never see
他们可能
their kids again because they might die
再也见不到自己的孩子，因为他们可能会
in The
在
Blitz right like that is
闪电战中丧生。这在
incomprehensible to a modern day and yet
现代人看来是难以理解的，然而当时这样做却完全合情合理。
that made total sense that we stayed
我们留下来
back to support the war effort and to be
支援战争，成为战争的
a part of it and we sent the kids to the
一份子，把孩子送到
country in the United
乡下。在美国，
States more people died by Suicide who
更多的人因为
didn't get called to
没有被征召而自杀。这真是
action the shame of not being call to
耻辱。 未被召唤去
serve was more overwhelming than the
服役比被
call to service there were more suicides
召唤去服役更令人难以承受。
in the United States from people who
在美国，
didn't get called to serve what does
未被召唤去服役的人自杀人数更多。
this say about the the genz the
这说明了什么？对于正在
millennial now that's trying to decide
努力决定人生方向的Z世代和千禧一代来说，他们似乎更倾向于选择
be a lawyer is the clear incentive
律师这个职业，
because I'll get paid more or my you
因为这样收入更高，或者
know people would be more proud of me on
在
Instagram if you're saying that service
Instagram上获得更高的关注度。如果你说的是服务，那么
challenge is so Central to being happy
挑战似乎也与幸福息息相关。
how does like the young person decide
年轻人该如何
like make build their life road map what
规划自己的人生路线图？
do they what do they need to be adding
他们需要
to that road map got this kid in my head
在路线图中添加什么？我脑海中浮现出一个孩子，
screen he's spending all his time on the
他现在整天沉浸在电子游戏屏幕前，
internet watching um certain male
上网观看一些男性
influences that are telling him to be
榜样，这些榜样告诉他要“
individualistic he doesn't have a
个人主义”。他没有
romantic relationship in the world
恋爱关系，
doesn't have any friends he's not really
没有朋友，
leaving the house much not going to the
很少出门，也不去
gym at all often refer to these IND
健身房。人们常常把这种“个人主义”比作
internet and the rise in that type of
网络上的“非自愿独身者”（incel）。
individual according to a lot of people
据我跟很多人
I've spoken to is is rising because of
聊过，这类人的数量上升是因为当今
the nature of the world and
世界的现状、人际关系的疏离、
disconnection and lack of friendship and
友谊的缺失
all these things you know what' you say
等等。你知道，当你
to that person who's probably a guy
跟一个可能正在
looking at the statistics well well you
看统计数据的人（比如
Scott Galloway yeah you know he's he
斯科特·加洛韦）说这些的时候，你会怎么说？
talks a lot about this you know um and I
嗯，你跟他聊过，他经常谈到这个话题。我
don't think we talk enough about this as
觉得我们对这方面讨论得还不够，尤其是在它与
it relates to extremism and terrorism
极端主义、恐怖主义之类的联系上。
and things like that you know
想想看，一个
where you take a 24 25 26 27 year old uh
24、25、26、27岁的
incel
单身
virgin with no social life there's a lot
处男，没有社交生活，他内心积压了很多
of pent up frustration there and that
挫败感，这些挫败感会以
comes out in all kinds of screwed up
各种扭曲的
ways usually anger usually victimization
方式爆发出来，通常是愤怒、受害者心态、成瘾、报复
Behavior you know antisocial behavior um
行为、反社会行为等等。
um and if you look at you know even just
如果你看看过去
statistic this is decades and decades
几十年的数据——这可不是最新的统计数据，而是几十年的数据——
and decades but you look at sort of the
你会发现，
rise of uh ex religious extremism in the
前宗教人士的数量一直在上升。
Middle East you know you take a shame
你知道，中东的极端主义就像一个以羞耻感为
based society where you're 24 25 26
基础的社会，你24、25、26
years old you're living at home you're a
岁了，还住在家里，还是个
virgin um the only way you can leave the
处男。你唯一能离开
house is if you like get a job and if
家的办法就是找到工作，但如果
you get you won't get a girlfriend and
你找到了工作，就没法找女朋友，也就是没法结婚，也就是没法发生
I.E a wife I.E have sex until you get a
性关系，直到你找到
job and move out of the house and so
工作搬出去为止。
this there's the and and and and you're
这就是问题所在。你
in a in a shame based society like the
身处一个以羞耻感为基础的社会，压力
the pressures are extreme and the anger
和愤怒都极其
is Extreme um so I think yeah I think
巨大。所以我觉得，
this idea of not knowing how to make
不知道如何交
friends and finding online community of
朋友，却在网上找到一个互相支持、互相安慰的“受害者”群体，这种想法本身就极具煽动性。
victimhood is is incendiary I could
我永远无法
imagine Simon cynic in one of your books
想象西蒙·辛尼克会在你的书中对
telling people that they were losers
别人说他们是失败者，说他们是废物，说他们很糟糕。
oh yeah never do that but when I look at
哦，当然不会那样做。但当我看到
Andrew Tate's approach in his videos
安德鲁·泰特在他的
multiple videos and tweets he really
视频和推文中的做法时，他真的在
mocks the people that he's speaking to
嘲讽他正在谈论的人，
he says your life sucks you're an
他说“你的生活糟透了，你……” 一个
absolute loser and then he tries to
彻头彻尾的失败者，然后他试图给
offer them a road map yeah and it seems
他们提供一条出路，是啊，而且似乎
to work yeah of course it works why cuz
奏效了，当然奏效了，为什么呢？因为
you're validating their feelings of
你认可了他们的
victimhood you're affirming it and then
受害者心态，肯定了这种心态，然后为
offering them a way out um because if
他们提供了一条出路。嗯，因为如果
you simply say everyone can be a winner
你只是说每个人都能成为赢家，
like and I don't feel like a winner
而我觉得自己不是赢家，那
you're not talking to me but if I say
你就不是在跟我说话。但如果我说
you've been forgotten like look we we we
你已经被遗忘了，就像我们
do it in work all the time it's like the
在工作中经常遇到的情况一样，感觉
corporation doesn't care about you the
公司根本不在乎你，
corporation prioritize its profits over
公司把利润放在
you you're like yeah like you're
你之上，你就会觉得，是啊，就像你随时可以被
disposable yeah it's kind of a
抛弃一样。嗯，这有点像是一种
rhetorical clickbait right because what
修辞性的标题党，对吧？因为
you're doing is you're validating
你实际上是在认可
someone's feelings you make them feel
别人的感受，让他们觉得自己并不
not alone in their loneliness and
孤单，不再感到孤独和
victimhood and then you offer them but
受害，然后你给他们提供——
you're not just berading them you're
你不是在指责他们，你是在
offering them a validation and then a
肯定他们，然后给他们提供一条摆脱
and a an a way out of that feeling um
这种感觉的出路。嗯，这并
and it's not wrong it's it's too much
没有错，只是有点
like it's totally fine for you and I to
过头了，你我完全可以这样
say look if if if you feel like your
说：如果你觉得…… 就像你的
career isn't going anywhere and yet you
事业毫无起色，但你却有很多
have ideas that you think of how you can
想法，想着如何才能
do it better maybe maybe an entrepreneur
做得更好，也许创业更适合
life is for you like we're we're saying
你。我们说的其实很
similar things the difference is is
相似，区别在于
we're not berating people right but we
我们不会责备别人，但我们
we definitely want people to feel
绝对希望别人感到被理解。
seen right um I just think you know when
嗯，我觉得你知道，当
you play in the extremes you're playing
你走极端的时候，就会
get extreme behaviors extreme reactions
出现极端的行为和反应。
you know you you could do the same thing
你知道，你完全可以
to the same people without riling them
对同样的人做同样的事情而不激怒他们，
up because emotions are a powerful thing
因为情绪的力量很强大。
right and so you're playing with the
所以你现在玩的是“情绪波动”的游戏。
Delta I'm going to push you down even
我会把你打得
harder you know and then I'm going to
更惨，然后又会向
show you that I can lift you even higher
你证明我可以把你捧得更高，然后
and I must you know that must make me
你就会觉得我是
the savior because the Delta is so much
救世主，因为“情绪波动”太大了。
bigger you know if someone is listening
你知道，如果有人正在听，
now and they are they have no friends
他们没有朋友，很
and they're lonely MH and they're
孤独，而且
also and there's someone else that's
还有另一个人正在
listening and they are single
听，他们是单身，
romantically single mhm
恋爱中的单身。嗯，
the first step to solving those two
解决这两个
conundrums finding a friend and finding
难题的第一步就是找到朋友和找到伴侣。 就我而言，在
to in a modern world where
如今这个
digitalization has just you know social
数字化时代，社交
networking exists and Tinder exists what
网络和Tinder等软件层出不穷，那么，我该去哪里寻找伴侣呢？
is that place the location because I
因为我身边
have so many conversations with people
很多人都在为
fronts to find a friend and to find a
寻找朋友和
partner where they're saying I just hate
伴侣而苦恼，他们说自己讨厌
dating apps and then um we've now have
约会软件，现在又有了
friendship dating apps I'm wondering
交友软件。我不禁思考，如今的“寻找伴侣”究竟在哪里？以前，
know once upon a time it would be in the
它可能在
village it would be maybe at church it
村子里，可能在教堂，或者
would be at you know somewhere in person
某个地方，人们会面对面地交流。但随着人们
building friendships or romantic
建立友谊和恋爱
relationships it feels like both groups
关系的能力下降，感觉这两类人都面临着
are struggling and I've got a particular
困境。我有个
friend in mine that I don't know what to
朋友，我不知道该如何
say to her about this subject cuz she's
跟她谈论这个话题，因为她非常
finding desperate to find someone
渴望找到
finding a partner is as difficult as
伴侣，但她发现找到伴侣和
finding a
找到
friend um and and it's different for
朋友一样难。而且，
introverts and extroverts right so like
内向者和外向者的情况也不一样。
me take me for example I am absolutely
就拿我来说，我完全
socially inept in Social places parties
不擅长社交，在社交场合，比如派对、
bars clubs networking events I am
酒吧、俱乐部、社交活动，我都会感到
absolutely uncomfortable and inept I
非常不自在和笨拙。 我经常一个人待在
stand in a corner by myself and the
角落里。说起来也挺
funny thing about my career it's
搞笑的，我的职业生涯里
actually been helpful that some people
有些人
recognize me because they'll come up to
认识我，这其实挺有帮助的，因为他们会主动过来跟我搭讪，这让我感觉轻松多了。嗯，
a relief right my my my um one of my
我
best friends makes fun of me cuz she
最好的朋友之一总是取笑我，她
says like when we go to like a when we
说，比如我们去参加
go to a party like when we go to like
派对，或者去
like a part party at someone's house or
别人家参加那种有
something and there's like 100 people or
100人左右的聚会，大概有
whatever there is 50 people that all
50个人吧，大家都在
these conversations are happening like
聊天，就像
you know these like little pockets of
那种小圈子的对话一样。
conversations and I don't know how to
我不知道怎么
inject myself into com I don't know how
融入进去，不知道怎么才能不显得很
looking really uncomfortable and weird
不自在、很怪异，不破坏气氛，不破坏
whatever Dynamic exists and so she makes
现有的互动模式。所以她就
fun of me because I'll just stand by
取笑我，因为我一个人站在
myself in the middle of the room with my
房间中央，手里拿着
drink perfectly comfortable but like
饮料，感觉很自在。但当
when she stands in the corner and looks
她站在角落里，环顾四周，
around like she goes to like get
比如去拿
something she'll see all these little
东西的时候，她会看到各种小圈子的
conversations and one person standing by
对话，只有一个人一个人拿着
themsel with their drink and it's me so
饮料站在那里，那就是我。所以，
I'm useless in Social places it's the
我感觉自己完全没用。 在社交场合，
introvert in me but in unsocial places
我的内向性格会让我感到不自在，但在非社交场合，
I'm more relaxed so
我会更放松。
like put me in a
比如，把我放在
museum and I'm looking at a piece of art
博物馆里，我正在欣赏一件艺术品，
and somebody next to me is looking at a
旁边的人也在欣赏，
piece of art and I actually have no
我完全可以很
problem saying you like it
自然地说“你也喜欢这件作品”。
and it I'm not trying to make a friend
我并不是想和他们交朋友，
I'm but I do like making a connection
但我确实喜欢建立联系。
and sometimes I talk for them for 30
有时候我会替他们聊上30
seconds about the piece and it's
秒，谈论这件作品。这种情况
happened a couple times where we just
发生过几次，我们聊着聊着就停不下来了，
talking and then you end up having a cup
最后一起喝了杯
of coffee and you ended up making a
咖啡，就成了朋友。我就有过这样的经历。
that because of the shared interest you
这是因为共同的兴趣，你从
fundamentally know that you I think
根本上知道彼此有
there's a shared interest I also think
共同的兴趣。而且，我觉得，
and this is a weird thing I actually
这有点奇怪，但实际上，我
think it's easier to make a connection
觉得和别人并肩站着比和别人面对面站着更容易建立联系。
somebody so like in social situations
在
like bars clubs networking events you
酒吧、俱乐部、社交活动等社交场合，你们
you face each other which I find
面对面站着，我觉得这样很紧张，充满对抗感。
adversarial and tense and you have to
你必须
gauge the right amount of social
把握好社交
distance you know it's 18 Ines is
距离，18英寸（约45厘米）是
actually the right amount you know
合适的距离，比这更近就有点尴尬了。
anything less than that is like too
那样就
close anything that then too far is
太近了，太远又会感觉
weird you know but I find standing next
怪怪的，你知道吗？但我发现，
to somebody is easier if you like going
如果你喜欢
for a walk with somebody or strolling
和某人一起散步、漫步，或者
somebody in a museum standing next to
在博物馆里、
somebody in a buffet line you can
自助餐排队时站在某人旁边，那么和别人并肩而立会更容易，你
actually get really close without it
实际上可以靠得很近而不会感到不
being uncomfortable so any place where I
舒服。所以，任何我
can stand next to somebody I find it
可以和别人并肩而立的地方，我都觉得
less and and being quiet is easier when
不那么尴尬，而且保持安静也更容易。
you're next to somebody like when you go
比如你和
for a walk with somebody if you're
某人一起散步时，如果你
standing next to somebody you can say a
站在对方旁边，你可以说
few words and then you can go completely
几句话，然后就可以完全
quiet that's not awkward when you're
安静下来，这并不尴尬。但如果你
facing somebody you go completely quiet
面对着某人，你就会完全沉默，这会让你感到非常
it's just flat out uncomfortable so the
不自在。所以，
way I Define you know social versus um
我定义
like social environments versus
社交环境和
non-traditional social environments is
非传统社交环境的方式是：
am I standing next to someone or
我是站在某人旁边还是
standing across from someone
站在某人对面？
what's something that you're um
你有什么困扰？
struggling with and when I ask that
当我问这个
question I'm talking
问题时，我指的是
about where I feel like every time I've
我觉得每次我
met you but also every time we've met
见到你，或者说每次我们见面，
we've both been at Crossroads and those
我们都处于人生的十字路口。这些
Crossroads are professional Crossroads
十字路口包括职业十字路口、
personal Crossroads
个人十字路口
Etc um I'm at so many Crossroads in my
等等。我的人生中有很多十字路口，
life I think that's so where where tell
我想这就是原因。告诉
me so many Crossroads so trying to
我，我有很多十字路口。所以我试图
understand get a clearer idea on what my
理解，更清楚地了解我的
North Star is professionally and
职业北极星是什么，以及
therefore what I should be prioritizing
我应该优先考虑什么。
and this really relates to like
这其实与生活息息相关，甚至
it's not even professionally it's just
不仅仅是职业方面，就像
about I i' I've worried for a long time
我有很多关于……的想法。 我一直很担心，
that the way I'm living my life is going
我现在的生活方式最终会变成……
be um my priorities were wrong and that
嗯，我的优先事项错了，
I allocated my my time when I was young
我年轻时分配时间的方式不对，我把精力
allocated towards were like
放在了
work and material success and all those
工作、物质成功等等这些事情上。
things and that you know I heard there's
你知道，我听过
a story you've probably heard it before
一个故事，你可能以前也听过，讲的是一个
about the fisherman who
渔夫，
was down by the he had a little boat and
他有一条小船，
he went out to see every day and he went
每天都出海捕鱼。他
out and caught two fish and came back by
出海捕到两条鱼，
lunchtime he sold one fish to pay for
中午回来的时候，他卖掉一条来支付
the boat the petrol and the servicing
船的油费和保养费用，把
and he s he gave the other fish to his
另一条鱼给了
family to feed his family and then then
家人吃。然后，在
in the evenings and afternoons he spent
傍晚和下午，他
the time at the beach relaxing with his
和家人一起在海滩上放松。这时，
family and like a guy comes past in a
一个开着
Mercedes and is like listen listen I've
奔驰的人经过，说：“听着，听着，我
got an idea for you what we're going to
有个主意。
do is we're going to keep you out on the
我们打算让你
boat all day you're going to catch four
整天待在船上，你捕到四条
fish we'll C with the extra two fish
鱼，剩下的两条
we'll get other boats we'll employ
我们用来买其他船。” 我们会雇佣
people we'll increase the F Fleet we C
员工，我们会扩大F船队，
we'll catch loads more fish with all
我们会用
these new boats we have them we'll take
这些新船捕捞更多的鱼，我们会让
the company public we'll sell it and
公司上市，我们会把它卖掉，然后
then the Fisher man's like and then what
渔民会问，然后呢？然后
and he goes and then you can spend the
他就会说，然后你就可以
day with your family on the and I kind
和家人一起度过一天了。我
of look at how I've played my life and
回顾自己的人生，我穿的衣服，
I'm wearing that's how I'm playing my
这就是我
life a little bit um there's obviously
人生的一部分。嗯，显然还有
all all these other things like I'm in
其他的事情，比如我正处于
the face season of life where I'm
人生的一个关键阶段，我在
thinking about fatherhood and becoming a
思考为人父，成为一名
dad and how old are you now
父亲。你现在多大了？
31 so I'm right at that that age and my
31岁。我正好在这个年纪，我的
partner's 31 so um that's a you know a
伴侣也31岁。所以，嗯，这是一个
crossroad I'm at and uh so what do you
十字路口。那么，你打算怎么办？
it I don't know well what are you
我不知道。你在
thinking about I'm I think I'm
想什么？我想我正在
collecting evidence to form a
收集证据来形成一个
perspective that's [__] you have a
观点。胡说，你已经有了
perspective you don't need evidence you
观点，不需要证据，你已经
have all the EV you talk to you do this
拥有了所有证据。你和你交谈过。 你每天都做这个
podcast every day of your life yeah you
播客，是啊，你
talk you do no none of the talking on
说，你做，不，
your podcast you do of the listening I'm
你播客里说的都是听的，我
on to
看穿
you and we're going to go to ad break
你了，我们
now yeah uh so that's nonsense you have
现在要插播广告了。是啊，所以这都是胡扯。你有
an opinion you have a perspective I'd
观点，你有看法，我
like to know what that perspective is
想知道你的看法是什么，
because you're at a Crossroads where you
因为你正处于人生的十字路口，你
said yourself I'm questioning the
自己也说过，你在质疑我
priorities I made yeah so that means you
所做的优先事项。是啊，这意味着你
have a point of view and I'm worrying
有观点，而我担心
that I'm bullshitting myself about why
我是在自欺欺人，不知道
I'm working so why what is the [__]
我为什么工作。所以，
line you're giving yourself why are you
你给自己找的借口是什么？你为什么
working what's the [__] line what's
工作？你的借口是什么？你的
the [__] answer to that it's like
答案是什么？就像
the fisherman it's like and then I'll
渔夫一样，他会说，然后我会，
and then I'll make more boats and then
然后我会造更多的船，然后
we'll make more boats and then for what
我们会造更多的船。那么，为什么？
reason to what end like why is it
最终目的是什么？为什么
important for you to keep having all
对你来说，让所有
those boats in the water so I wonder
这些船在水里航行很重要？所以我想知道，这是
whether that it's about the end or if
为了最终目标，还是仅仅为了
it's about just the the fun of the
享受
journey and that's what I'm that's kind
过程？ 这就是我，这就是
of what I'm not sure is it about the end
我不确定的地方。这究竟是关于终点，还是关于
in the future which sounds like [__]
未来能够拥有更大的自由？这听起来像胡扯，
because I've got so much Freedom now or
因为我现在已经拥有很多自由了。或者，
is it life is just about the climb not
人生的意义在于攀登的过程，而
not getting to the top and having this
不是到达顶峰欣赏
incredible view but I just have to keep
壮丽的景色。我必须让自己的
life that's why I'm giving myself more
生活充满挑战，这就是为什么我给自己设定了
responsibility setting myself bigger
更大的
goals bigger challenges because the joy
目标和挑战，赋予自己更多的责任。因为
of life is waking up in the morning and
生活的乐趣在于每天早上醒来，
feeling a little bit scared about today
对今天感到一丝恐惧。
and you know okay so if that's the
如果
answer then you wouldn't be at a
答案是这样，你就不会站在人生的
Crossroads you would this wouldn't be a
十字路口，我们也不会有这场
conversation so so here's the blunt
对话。所以，直截了当地
question yeah what in what in your life
问你：你生活中的什么出了问题？
is off I think it's probably the balance
我想可能是
of my romantic relationship I feel like
我的恋爱关系失去了平衡。我感觉
I'm
自己在
deferring I feel like I'm telling myself
拖延，我感觉自己一直在告诉自己，
that I'll have I'll really focus in the
我会好好经营
way that I need to on my romantic
我的恋爱
relationship which is also going to then
关系，而这段关系将来也会
become my
成为我的
family in the future and I've been
家庭。我
especially this year I've been doing
尤其…… 我这
that all year I think that I'll have
一整年都在做这件事，我想
time for my relationship in three years
三年后
when I sell a business or something
等我卖掉公司或者做点别的，我就会有时间谈恋爱了。我一直这么
that's what I've been telling myself and
告诉自己，但
I think I'm I feel that
我感觉自己和恋爱关系之间存在
disconnection not just in my romantic
隔阂，不仅仅是在恋爱
relationships but I just feel that
关系上，而是在恋爱关系上。
disconnection because I've told myself
因为我告诉自己，
now that I I'll figure it out in 3 years
三年后我会解决这个问题，到时候
that's when I'll Focus I'll sell this
我会集中精力，卖掉
business then I'll focus on you know
公司，然后专注于……你知道吗，
what's so funny is
最可笑的是，
that if it was a business problem if you
如果这是一个商业问题，如果
and I were talking about a business
我们在谈论一个商业
problem and I was telling you about a
问题，我告诉你
business challenge I'm having I'm having
我遇到的挑战，
and if I said to you you know what
如果我说，你知道吗，
whatever I'll figure it out in 3 years
三年后我会解决的，你肯定会
you would say no you figured that out
说，不，你
now MH cuz that problem will not go away
现在就应该解决这个问题，因为这个问题不会消失，
and 3 years from now you'll defer
三年后你又会把这个问题拖延
another 3 Years or new problems you like
三年，或者新的问题出现。
if this was a business problem you would
如果这是一个商业问题，你
never let yourself defer that problem
绝不会让自己把这个问题拖延
for 3 years so how are you giving
三年，那么，你为什么
yourself a different standard for your
对
romantic relationship of something that
恋爱关系——如此
is of utmost importance to you the
重要的事情——设定了不同的标准呢？ 对你来说，将来
desire to start a family one day why do
组建家庭的愿望如此重要，
why the different standard for your per
为什么你对
a lower standard for your personal
个人
relationship than your professional work
关系的标准要低于对职业工作的标准呢？
I think sometimes our romantic
我认为，有时我们的恋爱
relationships becomes the residual
关系会变成剩余
benefit
利益，
I gets whatever's left it's kind of what
我只能得到剩下的东西。这有点像你之前
you were saying about friendships when
说的友谊。当
you was talking about friendships I was
你谈到友谊时，我
thinking that's that term residual
想到的就是“剩余
beneficiary like you get whatever's left
受益人”这个词，就像你只能得到剩下的东西一样。
it's not allocated in the calendar so if
它没有被安排在日程表上，所以如果
there's nothing in the calendar it gets
日程表上没有安排，
nothing that day but the business
那天就什么也得不到，但商务
meeting gets priority the thing I think
会议却优先。我认为
relationships are become the residual
人际关系之所以会变成剩余
beneficiary because it's unclear in the
受益人，是因为在
near term the impact of neglecting them
短期内，忽视它们的影响并不明显。
so like brushing not brushing your teeth
就像今天不刷牙，
today you would really see it today you
你
won't see the pain today there'll be no
今天不会感觉到疼痛，也不会去看
Dental visit don't brush it every day
牙医。
this week you also won't see the impact
这周不每天刷牙，你也不会感觉到影响。
don't do it for 5 years divorce you're
五年后离婚，你才需要去看
in the dental check having the MERS
牙医，
pulled out and these things in life
拔除麻疹等等。生活中有很多事情，
where they're easy to do and therefore
做起来容易，所以也
easy not to do and the the impact is
容易不做，而影响又会
delayed they always become residual
延迟显现，它们总是会变成剩余利益。
beneficiary and like that's that's the
受益人，这就是
nature of my life like friendships
我生活的本质，就像友谊、
family relationships I've got this
家庭关系一样。我
meeting today and I can quantify the
今天有个会议，我可以量化这次
return the meet the meeting is going to
会议的回报，它会给
make me a million or whatever but the
我带来一百万或者更多，但是
relationship not missing the date today
关系本身，比如今天不错过约会
or not checking on you're trading you're
或者不联系，你是在用坚持换取
trading uh consistency for intensity
强度，就像用
brushing your teeth every day for going
每天刷牙换取去看
dentist so intensity easy to quantify
牙医一样。强度容易量化，
easy to measure immediate result yeah
容易衡量，立竿见影的效果，是啊是啊是啊。而
consistency slow no easy way to
坚持则很慢，很难
calculate have to believe how long yeah
计算，你得相信需要多久，是啊，
like how long does it take to get into
就像要多久才能恢复
shape I don't know neither does any
身材，我不知道，
doctor how many days do I have to brush
医生也不知道。我需要每天刷牙多少天？
my teeth every day what if I take a day
如果我休息一天呢？
off that's fine how many days can I take
没关系。我可以休息几天？
off I don't know and Ne so
我不知道。所以，
consistency going to the
坚持就像
relationship like going to the gym yeah
去健身房一样，你不会把你们的关系当成去健身房一样对待，对吧？
right which is basically you're out of
基本上，你
shape and you're like I'll go to the gym
身材走样了，你会想，
when I have time and then you're
等我有时间再去健身房，然后你
surprised that you're out of shape and
惊讶地发现自己身材走样，
out of breath so you recognize this and
气喘吁吁，所以你意识到了这一点。
so the question is is what can you do
问题是，你能做什么？
and by the way you can also just
顺便说一句，你也可以自己去
discover the results all by yourself no
发现结果。不，
I don't want to right cuz I've got
我不想这么做，因为我有一些
friends I met one at shortage house the
朋友。前几天我在Shorthouse遇到一个朋友，
other day and he said I don't know how
他说他不知道是怎么
it happened he go my wife was focusing
回事，他说：“我妻子专注
on her business I was focusing on mine
于她的事业，我也专注于我的事业，
we got 13 years in and the relationship
我们在一起13年了，我们的关系就这么
had just vanished and I don't really
消失了，我真的不
know when it happened by the way the
知道是什么时候发生的。”顺便说一句，反过来也一样，
which is if you invest in the
如果事情进展顺利，如果你像投资锻炼一样投资于一段
relationship just like you invest in
关系，
exercise you're like I don't even know
你会觉得“我甚至不知道自己什么时候
when I got into such great shape but
变得这么好”，但你
look at this right and it's what I have
看，这就是我
found is that what makes great
发现的：成就伟大的
friendships what makes great
友谊、伟大的
relationships and what makes great
关系和伟大的
businesses is not just the big things
事业的，不仅仅是那些大事，而是
it's the it's the countless little
无数的
things like a corporate culture saying
小事，比如企业文化，比如
a daily basis like it's the countless
每天都向每个人问好，对吧？正是无数的
little things that add up to build trust
小事积累起来，才能建立信任，
to build foundation and I think this is
奠定基础。我认为这是
Entrepreneurship which is entrepreneurs
创业的一大悲剧，因为创业者
have a unique gift to excel at the
有着独特的…… 有些人天生擅长那些
things that are easy to measure but how
容易衡量的事情，但有
many of them are really good at the
多少人真正擅长那些
things that are hard to
难以
measure you know um because what drives
衡量的事情呢？你知道，因为真正驱动
you
你的
is the ability to say look how much
是能够说“看看
effort I got but look at the return I
我付出了多少努力，但看看我
got for that effort and if I can't show
付出的回报是什么”。如果我无法向
you a return I can only say trust me
你展示回报，我只能说“相信我，
have faith that goes back to the
要有信心”。这又回到了
question of faith I need you to have
信心的问题上。我需要你有
faith you'll be like I don't know but
信心，你可能会说“我不知道”，但
you know intellectually so if so I'm
你理智上知道。如果是这样，我就
going to go so you're a man of action
要走了。所以你是个行动派，
and we're going to get on to you by the
我们接下来要好好谈谈你。嗯，
way mhm okay so you're a man of action
好的。所以你是个
your best you're a man of action if you
行动派，如果你
know that you're not prioritizing your
知道自己没有把感情放在首位，过度
overemphasizing work to the sacrifice of
重视工作而牺牲了
your relationship and that your
感情，而
relationship is getting the residual
感情只得到了次要的
benefits I mean I'm sure that makes your
回报，那你就是个行动派。我的意思是，我确信这会让你的
partner feel so special honey I love you
伴侣感觉很特别，亲爱的，我爱你，
I want you to have all my residual
我想让你享受我所有的次要
benefits I mean but you know what I have
回报。但你知道吗，
to say she's running her own business
她经营着自己的事业，
she's flying around the world doing her
她周游世界。 她做着
own thing and 13 years from now a studio
自己的事情，13年后，楼上会有一个工作室，那是
upstairs which is her business her
她的
breath work Studio MH so are you forcing
呼吸疗法工作室MH，所以你是在强迫
her to take a breath and for herself and
她停下来，为自己喘口气，给自己一些
take time what I'm trying to do is
时间吗？我正在努力尝试的是……是的，
trying toed yes I know you are you
我知道你很听话，你很
obedient to those date nights yeah these
遵守那些约会之夜吗？是的，最近我遵守，
days I am and is she uh yes but they're
她也遵守吗？嗯，是的，但是约会
not frequent enough and this this is a
不够频繁。这是
new thing we're trying so I I remember
我们正在尝试的新方法。我记得
the first time I had the conversation
第一次
with her about putting her in the
和她谈到把她安排进
calendar and when people hear that this
日程表的时候，人们一听到“
idea of scheduling time with each other
安排彼此相处的时间”这个想法，就会有一种本能的
negative reaction because what you think
负面反应，因为你会觉得
I'm like your work or whatever she
我好像在忙你的工作之类的。她一开始
wasn't like this a little bit um but
有点不高兴，嗯……但是
when I explained the whole residual
当我解释了“剩余
beneficiary thing which is everything
受益者”的概念，也就是
else is being scheduled and our
其他所有事情都被安排好了，而我们的
relationship isn't so I want our
关系却没有，所以我希望我们的
relationship to be equally more
关系
important than all these other things
比所有这些占据
that are taking my diary than we bought
我日程表的事情都更重要，我们
into it a little bit and that's helped
稍微接受了这个观点，这确实对
our relationship a little bit but then I
我们的关系有所帮助。但是，我
don't know this year i' really [__] it
不知道，今年我真的搞砸了。
up like cuz I just over I said yes there
就像我刚过去，我说是的，
too many things and she's got her
事情太多了，她也有自己的
business and I felt like we're too is it
生意，我觉得我们就像
like passing ships in the night are you
夜航的船只一样，你
good at taking holiday no oh holiday
擅长休假吗？不，哦，休假？
what the hell no no you work on a
什么鬼？不不，你
holiday yeah my whole team now I was I
休假也要工作。是的，我的整个团队，我当时……嗯，
well I went to I bought House in South
我去南非买了房子，
Africa so I went over there but I was I
所以我去了那里，但我从来
never it was as if so you do know right
没有……就好像……你知道，没有什么
that nothing undermines trust more than
比
telling your team you're taking a
告诉你的团队你要
holiday and then checking in every day
休假，然后每天都来查岗更破坏信任的了。是的，你
yeah know because it's basically what
知道，因为这基本上是在
we're saying is I don't trust you to do
说“我不信任你们，你们不能在
this without me which I know is not
没有我的情况下完成这项工作”，我知道这不是
true but that's what you're
真的，但你
communicating that I can't even take a
传达的信息是，我甚至不能
holiday without having to double check
休假，而必须仔细检查
everybody's work and make every
每个人的工作，做出每一个
decision as opposed to saying I'm going
决定，而不是说“我要去
on holiday if there's an emergency deal
休假了，如果有紧急情况，你们处理一下，
with it I'll see you in two weeks by
两周后见”。
and what you will find is everybody will
你会发现，每个人都会
work to a higher level because you let
更加努力工作，因为你让
them you know what it is though when I
他们知道发生了什么。不过，
was on holiday which was about two weeks
大约两周前我休假的时候，
ago I woke up every day wanting to do
我每天醒来……
the work of course you did it's called
当然，你想做这件事，你也做了，这叫
addiction so addiction yeah yeah
上瘾，所以上瘾？是啊，是啊，
probably you woke up every day to get a
你可能每天醒来都是为了寻求刺激。是
hit yeah I want it's it's how you get
啊，我想要它，这是你获得
your validation I played paddle in the
认同的方式。我早上打了桨板，
morning but then I wanted to come home
但之后我想回家
and get stuck in yeah but you talked
继续沉迷其中。是啊，但你说过要
about prioritizing your relationship
优先考虑你们的关系，
honey I'll be there in 2 hours I'm just
亲爱的，我两个小时后到，我先
going to spend some time checking email
花点时间查看邮件，
then we'll go for dinner he was on a
然后我们去吃晚饭。他也在用
bloody laptop as well not saying it's
笔记本电脑。我不是说这
healthy you just sound like well I can
健康，你只是听起来好像……
be an addict if she's an addict yeah it
如果她上瘾了，我也可以上瘾。是啊，
takes one of you to break the addiction
你们其中一人需要戒掉瘾，
and bring the other one along with I
并带动另一人一起戒掉。我
dare you to take a
敢打赌，你们可以去
holiday and just start with one day I'm
度假，就从一天开始，我甚至
not even saying two weeks one day you
不是说两周，就一天，你们
both leave your phones in the
俩都把手机留在
hotel what do you think is going to
酒店。你觉得
happen if I do that I think you'll
如果我这么做会发生什么？我觉得你们会
actually get along really well and have
相处得很好，玩得很开心。一
start there's always a withdrawal you
开始可能会有点压力，总会有戒断反应，你
might need to do it for two or three
可能需要连续两天或三天，
days in a row cuz the first day might be
因为第一天可能会非常
excruciating the second day not too bad
难熬。第二天…… 第三天还不错，
the third day you will bond like you've
你们的感情会比以往任何时候都更加深厚。我们
life actually um with her have planned a
计划
retreat this weekend for for three days
这周末去格拉斯滕伯里玩三天，
and the deal we have is no phones so we
约定是“不带手机”。“
have what does no phones mean going to
不带手机”是什么意思？
glastenbury this weekend alone okay does
这周末我们打算单独去格拉斯滕伯里。好吧，
that mean you won't check your phones
这意思是说你不能看手机吗？还是
does it mean you turn your phones off do
说你要关机？还是要
you put your phones in airplane mode if
调成飞行模式？说实话，
I'm going to be honest with you I think
我觉得
that's really important it means that
这一点很重要。这意味着
I'm still going to check my phones but
我还是会看手机，但
not when we're doing the activities so
不会在我们一起玩的时候看。
if if for example if I like you know
比如，
evenings if she's getting changed then
晚上她换衣服的时候，
I'll just quickly check my phone so can
我就会快速地看一眼手机。所以
I make a recommendation yeah you hold
我建议你全程拿着
her phone and she holds you hold her
她的手机，
phone and she holds your phone for the
她也拿着你的手机。
whole time so if you need to take a
这样，如果需要
picture of food or whatever take a
拍照，比如拍食物什么的，就可以用
picture with each other's phone you know
对方的手机拍照。
somebody's password MH you know and at
你知道，手机不用密码也能开机。而且，任何
no point do you say can I have your
时候都不要问她“我可以借用你的
phone if she goes to the toilet but she
手机吗？”。如果她去洗手间，她会
takes your phone with you with her and
拿着你的手机，
vice versa and you if you're in a
反之亦然。 和你一样，如果你一个人在
restaurant by yourself God forbid you
餐厅里，天哪，你只
have to just like look around for a
需要稍微四处看看，
little bit okay I'll do that try it okay
好吗？我会试试，好的。
well my old my my team are listening now
我的团队现在都在听着呢，
so they'll know that from Friday till
所以他们知道从周五到
Monday if you need me I'm in glass and
周一，如果你需要我，我就在玻璃房里，别
leave me alone po M yeah yeah so
来烦我。嗯，嗯，所以，
so it's it's a gift don't but don't
这是一份礼物，不要把它看作是
think of it as a selfish thing think of
自私的事情，把它看作是
it as an act of service and it's an act
一种服务行为，是
of service to two different people it's
对两个人的服务行为，是
an act of service to your relationship
对你们关系的服务行为，
but it's also an act of service to your
也是对你们团队的服务行为。嗯，
team mhm give them a break right and let
给他们一点休息时间，让
them let them solve difficult
他们去解决
problems I am a big Manchester United
难题。我是曼联的铁杆
fan and I travel all over the world one
球迷，我周游世界，对我来说，无论身在何处，
someone that never misses a game ever
从不错过任何一场比赛，
nordvpn because nordvpn allows me to
NordVPN 就是我的救星之一。因为 NordVPN 让我可以
watch the game in territories and in
在一些地区和国家观看比赛，而这些地区和
countries where it's often not available
国家通常由于
for a variety of different reasons but
各种原因无法观看比赛。但
it's not just about football it's
它不仅仅关乎足球，还关乎
websites movies that I can access and it
网站和电影。 我能访问它，它
helps me navigate those geographical
能帮我绕过那些地理
blockers and that's why nordvpn are both
限制，这就是为什么 NordVPN 既是
a sponsor of this podcast but a
本播客的赞助商，也是
lifesaver for me and it costs the same
我的救星。它
as a cup of coffee per month and not
每月的价格只相当于一杯咖啡的钱。不仅
just that when I'm accessing Wi-Fi
如此，当我访问世界各地的 Wi-Fi
networks around the world it gives me a
网络时，它还能提供
lot of security which is something that
很高的安全性，
I think we don't think about enough if
我觉得这一点我们往往考虑得不够。如果
you want to check out nordvpn for a
你想体验 NordVPN，现在
limited time only head to
限时优惠，请访问
nordvpn.com
nordvpn.com/doac，
doac and you can access our exclusive
即可享受我们的独家
deal which gives the Diary of CEO
优惠：CEO 日记的
listeners a huge discount plus four
听众可以享受巨额折扣，
extra months when you sign up to a
注册
2-year Plan and there's no risk with
两年套餐还可额外获赠四个月。NordVPN 提供
nord's 30-day money back guarantee so
30 天退款保证，让你零风险体验。赶紧
give it a try that's nordvpn.com doac or
试试吧！访问 nordvpn.com/doac 或
check out the episode description link
查看下方本期节目简介链接。
below what are you struggling
你最近在苦恼什么？
with um well I'm writing a book and
嗯，我正在写一本书，
writing a book
写书
is always personal conundrums
总是会遇到一些个人难题。
um I'm actually in a really good place
嗯，我现在状态很好。
right now um you know I think we've
你知道，我们之前也
talked about this like my big struggle
讨论过，我最大的难题
is um I've taken a huge break a big step
是…… 嗯，我休息了很长一段时间，大幅
back from public speaking and it was so
减少了公开演讲，而公开演讲曾经是
much of my life for so long that to some
我生活的重要组成部分，所以在某种程度上，
degree like I'm trying to reconfigure
我正在重新规划我的
what I want to do with my life you know
人生方向。你知道，
I feel like I just sort of left
感觉就像我刚从
University and I'm like okay now what do
大学毕业，然后就不知道该怎么办了。
I do um so I'm I'm on a journey but I'm
嗯，我正在经历一段旅程，但我
I like it you left a lot of money off
知道，你放弃了很多钱，
the table many many many millions by
很多很多很多的钱，因为你
making that
做了那个
decision
决定。当然，那又怎样？
I don't that's not my
这不是我的
calculation I'm the person who I'm okay
考量。我这个人，
making less and lying on the
收入少一点，躺在沙滩上也无所谓。
have you know I want a comfortable life
你知道，我想要舒适的生活，
like anybody wants a comfortable life
就像每个人都想要舒适的生活一样，
but I don't
但我不需要
need to be the biggest richest most
成为最富有、最有
powerful I don't have that in me you
权势的人，我没有那种魄力。你
know I want to be really happy and I
知道，我想要真正快乐，我
want
想要
my friends to love me and I want to love
我的朋友爱我，我也想爱
my friends and
我的朋友。
um I don't
嗯，我不在乎
care like my my Tombstone won't have my
我的墓碑上不会刻着我的
bank balance on it you want to be
银行存款。你想
successful right in the things that you
在
commit yourself to of course but how I
自己投入的事情上取得成功，对吧？当然，但我对
define success you know money money I
成功的定义是…… 金钱，金钱，我
believe money is fuel right so I it's
相信金钱是燃料，对吧？所以，
not that I'm I'm this is not some hippie
我不是那种嬉皮士，
you know commune you know know thing um
你知道，也不是那种公社之类的，嗯，
I view money as fuel and um just like I
我把金钱看作燃料。就像我买车
don't I don't own a car just to buy
不是为了买
petrol I own a car to go places and I
汽油，而是为了去不同的地方。我
know the value of petrol is it'll help
知道汽油的价值在于它能带
me go
我去不同的地方，
places but I have to want to go places
但我必须想去不同的地方，
and I have to have destinations and so I
我必须有目标。所以我
view my life and my career as a car my
把我的生活和事业比作一辆车，我的
career is a car to help me go places and
事业就像一辆车，带我去不同的地方，
money is the fuel to to make that thing
金钱是让这一切
happen but I still have to have a
发生的燃料。但我仍然需要有
destination and I still have to look
目标，仍然需要经营好我的事业，保养好这台
machine to make it well oiled so it can
机器，让它运转良好，这样它才能
get from A to B but for me the joy is is
从A点到达B点。对我来说，乐趣在于
the journey that I take on the career
我在事业上的旅程，而
not how much petrol I have but if you
不是我拥有多少“燃料”。但是，如果你
did the speaking still if you did all
做了演讲，如果你做了所有这些，比如
this this you know flying around the
飞遍
world speaking you wouldd have more fuel
世界各地演讲，你就会有更多的“燃料”来完成你的
for the mission no I've heard that
使命。不，我听过那种
argument which is if you just doubled
说法，那就是如果你加倍努力
down for two years and like said yes to
两年，就像你说的“是”…… 如果你
absolutely everything and hated your
讨厌
life for two years you'd you'd you'd be
生活两年，你会觉得一切都糟透了，你会觉得一切都会
fine and the answer is yeah but what
好起来，答案是肯定的，但是
about those two years
那两年呢？
I I I you know and by the way
你知道，顺便说一句，我的
um I it's I it's the same mentality I
心态是一样的，我
want to work with people I like working
想和自己喜欢的人一起工作。
you know or I don't trust them even
你知道，有时候我会拒绝那些我不喜欢或者不信任的人的工作，即使……
though and um and people have accused me
有人指责我说，
it's like well you can afford to turn
你有能力拒绝
work down I was like I don't I've been
工作，我说我没有，我从有能力拒绝工作之前就开始
turning work down since before I could
拒绝工作了。在我有能力之前，
afford it um and I've been saying no to
我就一直在说“不”。
things before I could afford it and when
当
I was living hand to Fist and had no
我生活拮据、
money in my bank account I still lived a
银行账户空空如也的时候，我仍然秉持着
very similar philosophy because for me
非常相似的理念，因为对我来说，
my career was not just about advancing
我的职业生涯不仅仅是晋升，更是一路上的
it was about the joy along the way I I
快乐。
because I recognized when I worked with
因为我意识到，当我与
people who I didn't like working with I
我不喜欢的人一起工作时，我感觉自己真的在
literally found myself saying think of
寻找…… 总是听到“想想
the money think of the money think of
钱，想想钱，想想
the money think of the money and I would
钱，想想钱”，然后我就
exhausted and yet I would work with
筋疲力尽地离开。然而，我却能和
people who I loved working with and
自己喜欢的人一起工作。
sometimes I literally made zero like CU
有时候，我甚至一分钱都赚不到，比如在CU（可能是指某个公司或机构）。我会去做
I would like do volunteer stuff and I
志愿者工作，从中
had so much fun and I left supercharged
获得很多乐趣，离开的时候，我对
on life with more inspiration more ideas
生活充满热情，比开始时更有灵感、有想法，
and more friends than when I started and
也结交了更多朋友。
so I just came to the realization that
所以我意识到，这和我的努力程度
if it's got nothing to do with how hard
无关——我为这
I work I work really hard for both but
两份工作都付出了很多努力，但
one fills me with energy the other one
一份工作让我充满活力，另一份工作却让
saps me of energy and so no amount of
我精疲力竭。所以，
and my inspiration sapped and yet money
再多的钱也
cannot buy the energy ideas and
买不到
inspiration I get and so I I try very
我所获得的活力、想法和灵感。因此，我努力尝试，虽然并不
hard it's imperfect but I try very hard
完美，但我努力去做那些能让
to say yes to the things that fill me up
我感到充实的事情。
and some of them make good money and
有些工作能带来丰厚的收入，
some of them don't and that's okay um
有些则不能，但这都没关系。
and the reason I keep writing books and
我不断写作、
the reason I keep having ideas it's not
不断产生想法的原因，不是
because I'm smart it's not because I'm
因为我聪明，也不是因为我比
somehow more creative than other people
别人更有创造力，而是
it's because I'm surrounding myself with
因为…… 我身边都是些能让
people who fill me up give me energy and
我充满活力、
give me ideas but it's more than that
给我灵感的人，但这还不够，
because you're someone who is so
因为你非常
remarkably good at articulation and
擅长表达、
ideas and thinking through first
构思、从第一性
principles and really coming up with
原理出发思考问题，并且总能提出独到的见解。
the things I've always really wanted to
我一直
ask you is is
想问你的一个问题是：你的
the what is where does the inspiration
灵感来源是什么？
come from if people are s they're
如果人们富有
creative people or their you know they
创造力，或者他们
they just want to advance their own
只是想提升自己的
knowledge they want to be wise like you
知识，想变得像你一样睿智，
are what would you what would you
你会
recommend they did so and you talk about
建议他们怎么做？说到
first principles first of all I hate the
第一性原理，首先，我讨厌“第一性原理”这个
term first principles it's so
词，它太
condescending right let's just call it
居高临下了，对吧？我们还是把它叫做“
beginner's mindset right because that's
初学者心态”吧，因为
what you are you're basically pretending
你
that you're a beginner and you know
就是个初学者，你假装自己什么都
nothing it's or what I like to call it
不懂。或者我更喜欢称之为“
it's a student mindset I'm not an expert
学生心态”。我不是专家，
I'm a student I've always viewed myself
我只是个学生。我一直都把自己看作一个
as a student right and so my favorite
学生。 所以，我最欣赏那些敢于
people are the ones who ask the
问
questions that other people are
别人
embarrassed to ask because they don't
不好意思问的问题的人，因为别人
want to be seen as dumb students if
不好意思被当成笨学生。
you're in a classroom nobody Minds
在教室里，没人会不好意思
raising their hand and asking the
举手问
teacher how does that work because we're
老师“这是怎么回事”，因为我们都是
the students MH so I treat myself as a
学生。所以，
student in every meeting I don't mind
在每次会议上，我都把自己当成学生。我不介意
asking the questions that I don't know
问那些我不知道
the answers to even if it makes me look
答案的问题，即使这会让我看起来
like a fool I don't mind saying I don't
像个傻瓜。我不介意说我不
understand that I never try and be an
明白。我从不试图成为
expert in somebody else's business
别人领域的专家，
they're the expert in their business and
他们才是自己领域的专家。
so when you uh when you say like where
所以，当你问“
does the first principles come from
第一原理从何而来？”或者“
where does The Beginner's mindset I'm
初学者心态是什么？”的时候，我
not curious about everything I'm curious
不会对所有事情都感兴趣，我只对
about the things that I'm curious about
我感兴趣的事情感兴趣。
and I ask a ton of questions and I don't
我会问很多问题，而且我不
mind not knowing answers um I have
介意不知道答案。嗯，我有
strong opinions loosely held you know
很强的观点，但又不会固执己见。你知道吗，
somebody just told me the other day one
前几天有人告诉我，
of the things they liked about me which
他们喜欢我的一点是，
is like I'll come out swinging and I
我会一开始就全力以赴，
will argue hard for something but the
为某件事据理力争，但一旦
minute you give me a good argument or a
你放弃，我就会改变看法。 如果有人能给我一个有力的论据或
piece of evidence that proves me wrong
证据来证明我错了，我会说，
I'm like yep that's you're you're
没错，你说得
totally right I'm completely like again
完全对。但我又会说，
strong opinions loosely held right is
强烈的观点其实并不坚定，对吧？
though this is an impossible line of
不过，这种
thinking right and I'll tell you why
思路根本不可能，对吧？我来告诉你为什么。
that's like
这就好比
me asking Michael Jordan how do I become
我问迈克尔·乔丹“我怎样才能成为
a great basketball player it's like well
一名伟大的篮球运动员”，他会说“
you need some natural capacity like I'm
你需要一些天赋”，但我个子太
way too short so I lost that one and I
矮了，所以这个问题我答不上来。我
can work my brains out but I don't have
可以努力训练，但我没有
any Talent whatsoever so work ethic is
任何天赋，所以努力
definitely part of it and I can follow
肯定很重要。我可以学习
all of Michael Jordan's you know
迈克尔·乔丹的所有训练
routines and there is no chance zero
方法，但我绝对不可能
that I will become a great basketball
成为一名伟大的篮球
player not to mention the fact that he
运动员，更何况他从小就
started when he was a kid and I didn't
开始打球，而我不是。
so I think that you know people come up
所以，
to me sometimes and say I want to be a
有时候有人会问我“我想成为一名
public speaker how do I get into the
公众演说家，我该如何入
business I'm like well what do you want
行？”我会问他们“你想
to talk about they're like I don't know
讲什么？”他们会说“我还没想好”，我会说“
yet I'm like you've completely missed
你完全没理解我的意思，我从来
the point like I never wanted to be a
没想过要成为一名公众演说家”。 作为一名
public speaker I just had a thing that I
公众演讲者，我只是
wanted to talk about MH right and so you
想谈谈MH（心理健康）这个话题。你
have to have a passion for something and
必须对某件事充满热情，
then you figure out a way to bring it to
然后找到方法将其付诸
life you either become a an entrepreneur
实践。你可以成为一名企业家，
or you be you bring it to life in a
或者在
corporate environment or you it like
企业环境中实现它，或者
you find a thing and then you find the
找到一个想法，然后找到
way to bring that thing to life so
方法将其变为现实。所以，第一点
number one is like I don't think
是，我不认为
somebody can just choose to become me
有人能选择成为我，
like they can't choose to become you um
就像他们不能选择成为你一样。嗯，有没有什么
are there things that you could practice
方法可以练习，
that I've learned that will help you
可以帮助你
hone some particular skill set
磨练一些特定的技能？
sure um the courage to say I don't know
当然有。比如，勇气，我不知道，那是我付出
that one was a that was a hard learned
惨痛代价才学到的
lesson that was the greatest lesson I
教训，也是我一生中学到的最宝贵的一课。
ever learned in my life give me
给我
something technical in terms of how to
一些关于如何
deliver ideas and to speak that is
表达想法和演讲的技巧，一些
transferable could learn that's totally
可以迁移学习的技巧，
I can totally do that yep I totally give
我完全可以做到。是的，我完全同意。第一点
you that number one is what's the
是，你
motivation of why you're walking up on
走上
the stage or standing up in front of the
讲台或站在
room to give a presentation or you know
房间前面做演讲或推销的
giving a pitch right um what's the
动机是什么？是
motivation is it to get or is it to give
为了获得什么，还是为了……
um most people present to get something
大多数人参加试镜都是为了得到什么，比如获得
to get funding to get a client to get an
资金、客户、
Applause to get a book sale to get a
掌声、书籍销量或
follower right it's a it's a takers
粉丝，这是一种索取者的
mentality and I had learned to have a
心态。而我学会了培养
givers mentality and literally every
给予者的心态。实际上，每次
single time I have a meeting or I give a
开会或
speech I will say to myself under my
演讲时，我都会在心里默念：
breath out loud you're here to give I
你来这里是为了给予，我
have a point of you and I'm here to
有一个观点，我来这里是为了
share it and I don't want anything in
分享，我不求任何
return and that has profoundly helped me
回报。这对我帮助很大。
I just heard a thing that Michael Keon
我最近听到迈克尔·基顿
about about how he reconfigured his um
谈到他如何调整自己的试镜
uh mind mindset for auditions so the
心态。
problem with an audition the problem
试镜的问题在于，演员参加试镜的目的就是为了
audition specifically to get something I
得到什么。我
want the role so that I can be an actor
想要这个角色，这样我才能成为一名演员。
right I'm going to audition so that you
我去试镜，是为了让你
can give me the role so that I can be an
给我这个角色，这样我才能成为一名
actor want want want take take take
演员。想要想要想要，索取索取索取索取。
right and it's brutal and what Michael
这很残酷。迈克尔·
Keaton did is he stopped treating the
基顿的做法是，他不再把
audition as an act of selfishness gimme
试镜当作一种自私的行为，
and he started treating it as an act of
而是把它当作一种行动。
service which is that is I'm an actor my
服务，就是把一切都当作服务，当作给予。我是一名演员，今天我的
part today whether it's for 2 minutes or
角色，无论两分钟、
10 minutes or 15 minutes the part and
十分钟还是十五分钟，都是为了这个角色。
though I don't get paid my role today is
虽然我没有报酬，但我今天的任务是为
to play this part for my audience of
这三位观众表演。
sometimes if he didn't get the part that
如果他没能得到角色，他仍然会感到难过，因为
he's still a human being but his
他毕竟是个人。但
mentality of he treated the audition
他对待试镜的态度就像对待
like the role and the joy he got from
角色一样，他从表演中获得的快乐
being an act so he was a hardworking
让他成为了一名勤奋的
actor because he went to a lot of
演员，因为他参加了大量的试镜，
parts right and it's the same which is
而不是因为他得到了很多角色。同样的道理也适用于把
to treat everything as an act of service
一切都当作服务，当作
as an act of giving that the joy comes
给予。快乐来自于身处其中，来自于
meeting like I give good meeting right
开会。
because I enjoy meetings because I give
我喜欢开会，因为我会给予，
I give the people on the other side
我会把一切都给予对方。
everything and sometimes we do business
有时我们会
together and sometimes we don't but I
合作做生意，有时则不会。但我
often find meetings that go nowhere
常常发现，那些没有结果的会议也
really
很
enjoyable so one thing that everybody
有趣。所以每个人都
can learn is if you have a point of view
可以学习的一点是，如果你有观点，
or if you have a product if you have a
或者你有产品，或者你有
service that you think has value in the
你认为对世界有价值的服务，
world then show up with the joy of
那就带着给予的快乐去展现自己吧。
giving so number one is showing up to
所以第一点就是带着
give and uh and if you want like real
付出去出现，如果你想要一些真正的
technique for standing on stage I can
舞台技巧，我也可以
give you that too let's do both so on
教你，我们两方面都来。
the first point about showing up to give
首先，关于带着付出去出现，
if I show up with that mentality of I'm
如果我带着“我今天要付出”的心态出现，这是否也会
changes the content and the way that I
改变我的内容和方式？
Everything Changes Everything Changes
一切都会改变，一切都会改变，
the your tone of voice changes like
你的语气也会改变。
we've all experienced somebody who takes
我们都经历过索取者和
versus somebody who gives right go to a
付出者的区别，对吧？去一家
shop where the employee is paid by
员工拿提成的商店，
commission and tell me if you can feel
告诉我你能不能感受到？对对对。
it yeah yeah yeah now now go to a shop
现在，去一家
where the employees given a salary and
员工拿固定工资、
there's no commission for every sale and
没有提成的商店，
tell me if you can feel the difference
告诉我你能不能感受到天壤之别。
night and day night and day right so
所以，道理是
it's the same thing people are smart
一样的，
people can feel when you're a taker and
人们很聪明，他们能感觉到你是索取者还是
people can feel when you're a giver I
付出者。我
see it all the time on stages it's
在舞台上经常看到这种情况，当
really easy when somebody's on a stage
有人走上舞台，
first thing they tell you is put your
第一件事就是对你说“把
phones away give me an hour of your time
手机收起来，给我一个小时的时间，懂吗？给
I you know show me some politeness okay
我点礼貌，行吗，
[__] that's your job is to hold my
混蛋？” 你的工作就是吸引我的
attention you know
注意力，你知道吗？
uh when they stand up and they tell you
当他们站起来，告诉你
their credentials or just the logo being
他们的资历，或者只是
on the screen when they stand up and the
屏幕上显示他们的logo，他们站起来的时候，他们
screen behind them has their logo their
身后的屏幕上会显示他们的logo、
URL their all their all their QR code
网址、二维码，以及
all the handles for all their socials
所有社交媒体账号。
when you ask them a question and they
当你问他们问题时，他们会
say well if you read my book oh my God
说：“如果你读过我的书，哦我的天哪，对吧？还有
right uh my online course like you it's
我的在线课程，就像你一样。”他们根本控制不住
they can't help themselves it's they're
自己，简直是过度推销。
dripping people hate that on this
人们讨厌这一点。
podcast in one of our recent episodes a
在我们最近的一期播客节目中，
certain guest referenced their book
一位嘉宾每三句话就提到他们的书。说
section that honestly I was like gee why
实话，评论区里的评论多到我都想，为什么还要
have to have a chat about it as a team
作为一个团队讨论这件事呢？
because so many of the comments even
因为尽管那次谈话很
though it was a great conversation it's
精彩，而且那次谈话的
done millions and millions of downloads
下载量和观看量都达到了数百万，但很多评论都表达了对嘉宾
20 times in a three-hour conversation
在三个小时的谈话中提到他们的书20次的强烈不满。是
yeah but but you know but some in in
啊，但是，你知道，有些人会为他们
their defense especially firsttime
辩护，尤其是那些第一次出书的
authors but even multiple time authors
作者，但即使是多次出书的作者，
the Publishers give them bad advice yes
出版商也会给他们机会。 那些糟糕的建议，没错，
the Publishers say push the book push
出版商总是说要推销新书，推销
the book and I always tell people who
新书。我总是告诉那些
have a new book just come on and have a
有新书的人，来
conversation with me about what I want
和我聊聊我想
to talk about I'll make you shine don't
聊的话题，我会让你大放异彩，别
worry it'll be a wonderful conversation
担心，这会是一次很棒的对话。
and if people like you they will go find
如果人们喜欢你，他们就会去
out and they will buy your book and let
了解，就会买你的书，让
me plug it you just answer my questions
我帮你宣传。你只需要回答我的问题。是啊，没错。
yeah right I had a guest once who
我曾经有个嘉宾，嗯，也是一样，
um to same thing every my Netflix
每次都提到我的Netflix
special my new Netflix special my next
特辑，我的新Netflix特辑，我的下一个
Netflix special my first Netflix special
Netflix特辑，我的第一个Netflix特辑，
you know my third Netflix special on my
你知道的，我的第三个Netflix特辑，还有我
upcoming Netflix special like it was so
即将推出的Netflix特辑，真是太
gross and I I mean I shouldn't say this
恶心了。我的意思是，我不应该说这些，
on but but we edited I was so annoyed we
但是我们剪辑了，我当时非常生气，我们把
edited out every single mention and so
所有提到Netflix特辑的内容都剪掉了，所以
in that episode is zero you probably did
那期节目里提到Netflix特辑的次数是零。你可能帮了他们一个忙，因为
them a favor CU I took them all out um
我把它们都剪掉了。嗯，
but it was gross he wasn't showing up to
但是这太恶心了，他来不是为了分享，而是为了
give he was showing up to take and the
索取。
conversation he never engaged with me he
他从来没有和我进行过对话，他
had an agenda and I was simply some
有自己的目的，而我只是一个
platform the thing that I like about the
平台。我喜欢
podcast and you look you have guessed
播客的一点是，你看，你猜对了。
that you like more than others not
你更喜欢某些人，不是
because they're nice people it's because
因为他们人品好，而是因为
you realize that you're having a nice
你意识到你们在进行愉快的
conversation or you realize they're they
对话，或者你意识到他们
have an agenda agenda is a taking
有自己的目的——目的是一种索取
mentality um um so if there's so going
心态。嗯，所以，如果要说有什么
back to techniques that I've learned you
技巧的话，那就是……你知道，
know like even when I talk about my work
即使我谈论我的工作，
I'm talking about it in a way that I've
我也会用一种感觉，好像
like I've discovered something or I'm on
我发现了什么，或者我正在经历
a journey of something and I really want
一段旅程，我真心希望
people to come on the journey with me so
人们能和我一起踏上这段旅程。所以，
let me tell you what I'm learning as
让我告诉你我正在学习什么，而不是炫耀我
opposed to look how smart I am look at
有多聪明，看看我
the stuff that you should buy my book
写了些什么，让你买我的书。
and you know what is that at the the
你知道吗？
someone walks up on that stage or is in
一个真正欣赏走上讲台或在
that presentation room doing the pitch
演讲厅里做推介的人，是因为
when they can just feel in their bones
他们能从内心深处感受到
that this person came to give versus
这个人是来付出而不是
take what is it like the human level oh
索取的。这在人性层面上是什么呢？哦，
it's super simple right because we're
这很简单，对吧？因为我们是
highly attuned social animals our
高度社会化的动物，我们的
survival depends on our ability to trust
生存依赖于彼此信任的能力。
each other right think about where we
想想我们从哪里来，
came from we lived we're tribal animals
我们生活在哪里，我们是群居动物，
that if I fell asleep at night I need
如果我睡着了…… 晚上我需要
you to watch for danger and I need to do
你留意危险，我也需要
the same for you so we we're very very
为你留意危险。所以我们非常
good at assessing are you looking out
擅长判断你是在保护
for me are you looking out for you and
我还是在保护你自己。这种本能
so it's deep seated into our you know
深深植根于我们的原始
our caveman brain that if I sense that
本能中：如果我感觉到
you're a taker I I I'm not sure I want
你是个索取者，我就不确定
to fall asleep at night so where if I
晚上能不能睡着。但如果我
sense that you have a giver's heart like
感觉到你有一颗乐于奉献的心，
yeah I'll fall asleep at night and let
我晚上就能安心入睡，让
you I'll let you watch for saber 2
你帮我留意危险。
Tigers yeah so we're very very attuned
所以我们非常敏感，当然，
we can be tricked um we can absolutely
我们也会被欺骗，绝对会被
be tricked um but for the most part
欺骗。但大多数情况下，我们非常擅长
assessing we're pretty good at at at at
判断，非常擅长分辨
someone's a giver or a taker but like I
一个人是付出者还是索取者。就像我
said I am sympathetic I'm not judgy
说的，我很有同情心，不会妄下评判，
because I know some people it's born out
因为我知道有些人之所以会这样，是因为缺乏
of insecurity or incredibly bad advice
安全感，或者受到了
that they're given by their Publishers
出版商
or you know to push push push push push
或其他方面糟糕的建议的影响。 推推推推，
which is the wrong
这是错误的
advice just tell the story just tell the
建议，只要讲故事就行了，只要讲
story born out of insecurity it's funny
故事就行了，这源于不安全感。有趣的是，
I was watching a conversation with you
我今天早上看了你和一个人的对话，
you were asking them about their they
你问他们关于他们的……他们
asked you how how they find their why
问你如何找到他们的“为什么”，
yeah and you basically coaching them
你基本上是在指导他们完成
through that exercise and one of the um
这个练习，其中一个……你
you asked them about an early memory in
问他们童年早期的记忆，
their childhood or that they can
或者他们
remember from their career and you using
职业生涯中能记住的事情，你用
that as a way to kind of track their why
这个来追踪他们的“为什么”。
and the answer the first answer they
他们
gave you was actually just about
给你的第一个答案实际上只是关于获得
validation it was about their school
认可，是关于他们的
teacher to saying they couldn't do
老师说他们做不到
something and then the moment they
某件事，然后当他们
proved they could yeah and as I was
证明自己可以的时候……是的，当我
listening to that I thought God that's
听着的时候，我想，天哪，这不是“
not a why that's insecurity and so many
为什么”，这是不安全感。
of us probably including me um we've
我们很多人，可能包括我，都把……
confused the confused them I sometimes
搞混了。有时候，获得
validation can feel
认可会让人感觉
like
像是
purpose well that's an interesting
目标。嗯，这很有意思，这很
that's an interesting I was watching the
有意思。我看着这段
conversation going oh my God this cuz I
对话，心想，我的天哪，因为
cuz the person you were speaking to I
你对话的那个人我
know them yeah and I know think I
认识，是的，我知道，我认为
they're very very complicated very very
他们非常非常复杂，非常非常复杂，
they've said it publicly they're very
他们公开说过，他们非常……
insecure and I know who we're talking
缺乏安全感，我知道我们在说谁，
about yeah his response was all about I
没错，他的回应全是关于“我
proved my teacher wrong and I was stood
证明了老师错了”，我站在
there having this great career moment
那里，享受着职业生涯的巅峰时刻，
and look at me I finally done it yeah
看我，我终于做到了！是啊，
and as I was watching I was like that's
我看着他，心想这
not purpose that's
不是目标，这是不
insecurity and it's even for me in my
安全感。甚至对我来说，这在我的
life I think I I confuse if you look at
人生中也是如此。我觉得我有点糊涂了。如果你看看
the first page of my diary when I'm 18
我18岁时的日记第一页，上面写着“
it says says four goals before I'm 25
25岁之前要实现的四个目标”：
number one six-pack number two uh
第一，练出六块腹肌；第二，呃，
girlfriend number three rain drove sport
女朋友；第三，开车运动；第四，25岁
number four millionaire before 25 that
之前成为百万富翁。这
wasn't purpose this was all the things
不是目标，这些都是让
that made me insecure goal people I
我感到不安全的事情。我
think people confuse goals and purpose
觉得人们常常把目标和意义混淆，
but these all four things made me feel
但这四件事在我小时候都让我感到
insecure when I was a kid yeah never had
不安全。是啊，我从来没交过
a girlfriend skinny smallest kid of four
女朋友，瘦弱，四个孩子里最小的，
no money in our household and um never
家里没钱，呃，从来没
never could drive youngest in the year
开车，年级最小，
didn't have money these were this was a
没钱。这些是
list of my insecurities in Reverse yeah
我不安全感的倒叙。是啊，这很
that makes sense and I thought they were
合理，我当时以为它们是
my goal missions in life but I think
我的人生目标，但我觉得
that's normal you know I think we're all
这很正常。 我们都忙着回忆是
a jumble of who is it who said it it was
谁说的，这话
really nice which is you know we're all
真好听。你知道，我们都在
seeking validation from others and yet
寻求别人的认可。然而，
if you're if you re I forgotten who said
如果你……我忘了是谁说的，
it was brilliant but we're all seeking
这话真棒。我们都在寻求
validation from others and hoping people
别人的认可，希望别人
like us and yet if we can just remember
喜欢我们。然而，如果我们能记得去
to validate somebody else you're ahead
认可别人，你就领先一步了。
of the game you know we're all worried
你知道，我们都在担心
at what people think about us and
别人怎么看我们，担心自己是不是讲
whether I made the wrong joke or whether
错了笑话，说错了
I said the wrong thing and the reality
话。但现实
is nobody's thinking about you yeah
是，没人会想着你，
they're thinking about themselves and if
他们都在想着自己。如果
you can just validate other people and
你能认可别人，
again this goes to the skill of of of
这又回到了
service you know which is you have to
服务他人的技巧上。你知道，你必须
have a friend you have to learn to be a
要有朋友，你必须学会​​如何成为
friend
朋友。
um the one thing that I've learned of
嗯，我在
the course of a career and I'm now in
职业生涯中学到的一件事，我现在也步入
age is the people in my life matter more
中年了，那就是我生命中的人比
than I thought they did the friends in
我想象的更重要。我
my life matter more than I thought they
生命中的朋友比我想象的更重要。
did learning to be a human being matters
学会做人比
more than I thought it
我想象的更重要。
did being smart being successful having
聪明、成功、拥有
the six-pack having the Range Rover any
六块腹肌、拥有路虎揽胜，
of those things is fun but but the
这些都很有趣，但
people with whom I share those things
人…… 我与谁分享这些事情
matters more like going to the gym with
更重要，比如和某人一起去健身房比练出
someone matters more than the six-pack
六块腹肌更重要，
going on the adventure with someone in
和某人一起开着路虎揽胜去冒险
the Range Rover matters more than the
比路虎揽胜本身更重要，
Range Rover who I get to share money
我能和谁分享金钱、花钱、捐赠
with and spend money on and give money
金钱比我赚多少钱
away to matters more than the money I
更重要，
make um um what I do with recognition
我如何利用认可，
and how I use it to make other people
如何让别人
feel seen or heard matters more than how
感到被关注或被倾听比有
many people see or hear me and um and I
多少人看到或听到我更重要。我
think that's the single most important
认为这是
lesson I've learned in a career I think
我职业生涯中学到的最重要的一课。我认为
that answers the question about the
这回答了关于不
difference between insecurity and
安全感和目标感之间区别的问题，
purpose because insecurity is about me
因为不安全感是关于我自己的，
and purpose becomes who can I give this
而目标感则变成了我能为谁提供
you know what service exactly cuz none
什么服务，因为除非
of those things are fun unless I get
我能获得……，否则这些事情都不会有趣。
like and I have some friends who are
我有一些朋友
insanely
非常
generous and when I say insanely
慷慨，当我说非常
generous you just
慷慨时，你会
realize the joy that they get from
意识到他们从
sharing whatever they've accomplished
分享他们的成就中获得的快乐。
with and by the way I'm not just talking
顺便说一下，我说的不仅仅是
about financial success like a friend
经济上的成功，比如我的一个朋友
who's an incredible artist and loves to
是一位杰出的艺术家，她喜欢
share her art you know and if you're one
分享她的作品，如果你是
of her friends you will get one of her
她的朋友，你就会收到她的一幅
art this kind of I want to go back to
画作。 我想回到
the public speaking advice cuz I really
公开演讲的建议上来，因为我真的
want to get that from you but um this
很想从你那里得到一些指导。但是，这让
kind of do made me think about
我想到
corporations and Business Leaders and
企业和商业领袖，以及
how they can introduce service into
他们如何将服务理念融入到
their into their companies as a way to
公司运营中，从而
create better businesses well they've a
打造更优秀的企业。
lot of companies have misunderstood what
很多公司误解了
service means they think service is the
服务的含义，他们认为服务就是
company gives money to charity or we
公司捐款给慈善机构，或者我们
have a giving day where we all go take a
组织一个“捐赠日”，大家请一天
day off work and work for Habitat for
假去为“仁人家园”之类的组织做义工，
Humanity or something like that we all
或者
like the company sponsors a fund run and
公司赞助一场慈善长跑，
you know run raise money for charity or
为慈善机构筹款，然后给员工放
know a day off to go do the run and we
一天假去参加，大家都积极参与志愿活动。这些都
all volunteer like those things are good
很好，这当然是
um that's charitable giving and you
慈善捐赠，你
should do that but that's not purpose
应该这样做，但这并非服务的意义所在，这只是
giving right um real purpose real
捐赠而已。真正的意义在于，真正的
service is and we've talked about this a
服务，我们之前也稍微讨论过，在如今这个
day and age where coming to work or
时代，上班还是
staying home has controversy and um and
待在家里都存在争议，而且还伴随着
mental Fitness issues
心理健康问题，
attached how do I help redesign work so
我该如何帮助重新设计…… 努力工作，
that the people I go to work with feel
让我的同事们每天来上班时都能感到
safe heard
安全、被倾听、被关注。
like what can I do at the office to make
比如，在办公室里，我能做些什么来让
somebody else feel seen and heard and
别人感到被关注、被倾听、被
validated to protect somebody else's
认可，从而保护他人的
mental Fitness that's service teach
心理健康？这就是服务，教人如何做到这一点。
people that and this is one of the
这也是
reasons why you know I'm work so hard
我如此努力工作，甚至
and like built a whole company to teach
创建了一家公司来教授
human skills because the skills to do
人际交往技能的原因之一，因为
those things are not well understood and
这些技能并没有得到充分的理解。要
their skills remember cats don't have to
知道，猫不需要费
work very hard to be cats but it takes a
太多力气就能成为猫，但
lot of work to be a human being and most
成为一个真正的人却需要付出很多努力。
of us actually lack the skills to be a
事实上，我们大多数人都缺乏成为一个
good human being in things like
好人的技能，比如
listening active listening like do you
倾听，尤其是积极倾听。你
know how to hold space for somebody
知道如何为那些正在
who's struggling do you know how to do
挣扎的人提供支持吗？
that um do you know how to have a
你知道如何进行
difficult conversation can you have a
艰难的对话吗？你能在
conversation about race in your company
公司里就种族问题展开对话吗？
you know um do you know how to have um
你知道如何以一种对方能够接受
can hear it without being defensive um
而不产生防御心理的方式，给予对方非常棘手的反馈吗？
do you know how to have an effective
你知道如何有效地与比
your level higher or lower than you in
你级别高或低的人进行沟通
the corporate hierarchy and confront
并坦诚交流吗？
them because they did something that
因为他们做了让
upset you in a way that they will hear
你不高兴的事，你会想，
you like do you have any of those skills
你具备这些技能吗？
most people including people in
大多数人，包括其他人，都会这样想。
skills now the best part is those skills
现在很多身居领导职位的人都缺乏这些技能。最棒的是，这些技能
are teachable learnable and practice
是可以教授、学习和练习的。
every single one of them can be learned
每一项技能都可以被
by absolutely 100% of people just like
100%的人学会，就像
every single person on the planet can
地球上的每个人都能
learn to ride a bicycle you just have to
学会骑自行车一样。你只需要
do a little bit of the work and you're
付出一点努力，一开始可能会摇摇晃晃，
scrape your knees a few times but I
膝盖也会擦破几次皮，但我
guarantee you you'll get to the point
保证，你最终会达到条件反射般的熟练程度。
where it becomes second nature and so if
所以，如果
you want to build a company that builds
你想打造一家将
service and purpose into the company
服务和使命融入企业文化的公司，请
please please teach people human skills
务必教员工人际交往技能。
and don't ask me what the ROI is right
别问我投资回报率是多少，对吧？
like what's the ROI of your mother right
就像Gary Vaynerchuk说的那样，你母亲的投资回报率是多少？
like it's everything you and I have
就像我们之前讨论过的所有事情一样，
r of going to the gym one day nothing
去健身房一天的投资​​回报率是多少？
the answer is zero unless you do it
答案是零，除非你
every day and so if you have a company
每天都去。所以，如果你的公司里都是
filled with people who are brilliant
善于倾听、擅长应对
listeners brilliant at confrontation
冲突、善于
brilliant at expressing their feelings
表达感受、善于与人
brilliant at having difficult
进行艰难
conversations with each other watch what
对话的人，那么公司将会蓬勃发展。 其他人会关注
happens to productivity to engagement to
生产力、员工敬业度、
Innovation to loyalty to customer
创新、忠诚度、客户
service um just every metric on the
服务等等所有指标的变化，
planet and the most important one the
而最重要的指标是员工的
joy the people who come to work where
快乐。当
people say I love my job I feel like I'm
人们说“我热爱我的工作，我觉得自己是某个
a part of something bigger than myself
更伟大事业的一部分”时，这种快乐就显得尤为重要。
and it has nothing to do with the
这与
product or service we sell I get the
我们销售的产品或服务无关。我
ultimate Joy of taking care of the
最大的快乐来自于照顾我的同事，
people I work with and I feel taken care
也感受到同事们的关怀。这可以说是
is that's about the greatest gift you
你
can give to a company that's good
能给予公司最宝贵的礼物——优秀的
leadership by the way um so and that
领导力。顺便说一句，
service to society in the same and I
为社会服务也是如此。我之所以说它为
society is for a very simple reason
社会服务，原因很简单：
because if you learn all these skills
如果你学习了所有这些技能——
and my company teaches me these skills
我的公司教给我这些技能——
even if it's selfish because they want
即使这出于私心，因为他们
to make their office better and they
想让办公室变得更好，他们
want more Innovation and more
想要更多的创新、更高的
productivity and more engagement fine
生产力和更高的员工敬业度，那也很好。一个
great somebody who has a who's a better
更善于
listener and better at
倾听、更擅长处理
confrontation once you have that skill
冲突的人，一旦你掌握了这些技能，
you have that skill which means you go
你就拥有了这些技能。这意味着你
better able to hold space for your
可以把这些技能带回家，更好地陪伴你的
spouse or your girlfriend or your
配偶、女朋友、
boyfriend or your children which means
男朋友或孩子。 这意味着
you have now improved your relationships
你现在改善了人际关系，
which means they feel seen and heard and
这意味着他们比以往任何时候都更感到被关注、被倾听和被
understood better than they ever have
理解。
before and because they now know what it
因为他们现在知道这种
feels like they in turn instinctively do
感觉，所以他们会本能地将这种感觉传递
it for their friends and their neighbors
给他们的朋友和邻居，
and those people do it for their friends
而这些人又会将这种感觉传递给他们的朋友
and their neighbors and before you know
和邻居。不知不觉中，这种
it the ripple effect you have World
涟漪效应就会产生，最终带来世界
Peace because remember world peace is
和平。记住，世界和平
not the absence of conflict that's not
并非没有冲突，
what world peace means world peace is
世界和平的含义并非如此。
conflicts peacefully World Peace doesn't
世界和平是指能够和平地解决冲突。没有冲突的婚姻或关系是不存在的。成功的关系能够和平地解决冲突。世界和平并不
mean we all agree World Peace doesn't
意味着我们都意见一致，世界和平并不意味着我们都
mean we we all like each
彼此喜欢。
idea of being able to have those
能够进行那些
difficult conversations which is so
艰难的对话，
Central to the health and Trust of an
对于一个组织的健康和信任至关重要。
organization and I've really been
我
learning this recently um over the last
最近几年一直在学习这一点，
couple of years that you can probably
你或许可以根据
dissatisfaction in any team organization
任何团队、组织、
family
家庭
relationship based on their ability and
关系中成员进行令人
capacity to have uncomfortable
不适的
conversations yeah because there so many
对话的能力来预测他们内心深处的不满程度。是的，因为现在有太多
so many companies so many Founders so
公司、太多创始人、
many leaders that are listening right
太多领导者正在倾听。
now will relate to this idea of quiet
这与“隐隐不满”的概念有关。
dissatisfaction it is when some of your
当你的某些
expectations are being unmet by your
期望未能得到
colleagues your co-workers your employer
同事、合作者、雇主或其他任何人的满足时，无论出于何种
whatever and for whatever reason because
原因，比如
of the culture you've not felt or maybe
你没有感受到某种文化氛围，或者
you don't have the skills to address it
你缺乏解决问题的技巧，这种不满就会不断滋长，
and it's now growing and then eventually
最终导致
you'll either leave something will break
你离开、
the company will die
公司内部出现问题
to get even better at what advice do I
甚至倒闭。因此，我们现在需要开始教导这一代人如何进行那些令人不适的对话，尤其是在人际关系方面。这彻底改变了我的人际关系，也改变了我的事业。我正在努力提升这方面的能力。我需要哪些建议才能做得更好？如何才能更好地
to drag my teams up and to make sure
带领我的团队，并确保
that all of us collectively as a culture
我们所有人，作为一个整体，都在
are creating that culture of like having
营造一种能够进行
the difficult conversation today well
艰难对话的文化？首先，就像
number one like I said teach it right
我之前说的，要正确地教导别人。就像我
the I mean I said like I said before
之前说的，
which is I recognized that I didn't have
我意识到自己缺乏这些
the skills I recognized that I wasn't
技能，我意识到自己
able to teach people the skills I
无法教会别人这些技能，我
recognized my teammates didn't have the
意识到我的队友们…… 当时我们缺乏这些
skills and so we started to look for the
技能，所以我们开始寻找相关的
people the books the TED Talks so that
人、书籍、TED演讲，以便
we could learn so that we could be
学习，从而
better to each other and it was so
更好地与彼此相处。这些技能如此
valuable that we said okay well what if
宝贵，以至于我们想，如果
we taught this to other people as well
我们也能把这些技能教给其他人呢？
because I I would just be at a dinner
因为我经常在
table talking about how I had learned
餐桌上和别人分享我是如何学习到这些
the skill and how it benefited my
技能的，以及它们如何改善了我的
relationships and my work and somebody
人际关系和工作，然后有人会
says oh my God can you teach that to me
说：“天哪，你能教教我吗？” 我当时就想，
you know and I was like I guess that was
这
a lot of what drove the early stuff from
大概就是我们早期创业的动力，也就是
the comp from the optimism company you
乐观公司（Optimism Company）的初衷。
know that the where we teach human
我们教授人际交往
skills it was the skills that I lacked
技能，因为这些技能正是我所缺乏的，正是
it was the skills that I needed MH and I
我需要的。我四处
sought them out I went and took them
寻找这些技能，
from other places wherever I could get
从其他地方学习，只要能找到就去学习。我
them um and realize there was a distinct
意识到，世界上普遍
lack of these
缺乏这些
skills uh in the world and the best
技能，而
place to get them would be at work again
获得这些技能的最佳途径仍然是在工作场所，
because that's where the people are
因为那里聚集着很多人。
because if you turned around today and
如果你今天在
any level in a company and you said
一家公司工作，无论你身处哪个层级，如果你
listen and you just started giving like
开始认真倾听，并给予他人一些
un difficult feedback or you started
简单的反馈，或者开始
exhibiting that behavior on your own you
展现出…… 如果你的行为是你自己做出的，那
would be so unusual in the culture that
在文化中会显得非常不寻常，
that people wouldn't understand it so
人们会无法理解。所以
you can't just listen to us have this
你不能只是听我们
conversation then go into work it's like
聊完这些就去上班，这就像
being radically transparent with people
对别人完全坦诚一样。
no you can't don't do that don't do that
不，你不能那样做，千万别那样做。
but what you can say and I've done this
但是你可以说，而且我已经这么做了，就像
as what I've said even to my team I've
我跟我的团队说过的那样，我甚至
said out loud I realize that one of the
大声说过，我意识到
skills that I'm lacking in is ex I am
我缺乏的一项技能是表达能力。我正在努力
going on a journey to hone that skill
提升这项技能，
I'm going to be practicing I might
我会练习。我可能会
fumble it and get it wrong sometimes I
犯错，有时我的行为
might start acting in a way that you
可能会让你
will perceive as weird bear with me I'm
觉得很奇怪，请理解，我
just practicing a new skill I just want
只是在练习一项新技能。我只是想让
you to know that I'm on this journey so
你知道我正在努力，所以
when I start acting weird or differently
当我开始表现得奇怪或与众不同时，
you'll know why and the journey is I'm
你就会知道原因。我的努力是，我会开始
going to start trying to accept um
尝试更好地接受困难的
difficult conversations and feedback
对话和反馈，
better and I'm going to try and give it
并且我会尝试
more honestly and openly is that the the
更真诚、更坦率地表达出来。这就是重点吗？
essence I mean if that's the one you're
我的意思是，如果你正在
working on yeah you know um you know
努力提升的是这个方面，是的，你知道，你知道，
because I mean I took a listening class
因为我 我的意思是，很多年前我上过一个倾听课，
many years ago and here's what I
我
learned I learned that I am an
学到了一件事：我发现自己对
with people I will never speak to again
那些我这辈子都不会再联系的人，绝对是个超级棒的倾听高手；
for the rest of my life but with my
但对我的
friends and colleagues a freaking
朋友和同事，我的倾听能力简直糟糕透了。
disaster and so when I would have
所以，当我
arguments with friends and colleagues
和朋友同事吵架，
and they would say you are such a bad
他们说我根本不会
listener I would say seriously like do
倾听的时候，我就会认真地反驳说：“
you know what I do for a living I think
你知道我是做什么工作的吗？我觉得我
I'm doing just fine right and I was
做得挺好的，对吧？”我的确做得不错，
right but in a different context with
但前提是对方是
people who I will literally never see or
我这辈子都不会再见面或联系的人。
and so when I took this class I was like
所以，当我上了那个倾听课之后，我感觉
[__] and I remember when I was done with
糟透了。我记得
the class I picked up the phone and like
课结束后，我拿起电话，给
called a bunch of people I said I think
很多人打了电话，说：“我觉得
I owe you an apology I just took this
我应该向你们道歉，我刚上了这
class and I realized I'm a terrible
门课，我意识到自己是个糟糕的
listener and they were like yeah we know
倾听者。”他们说：“是啊，我们知道，
you know and yet they stuck with me
你知道的。”但他们仍然支持我，
still you know why would they do that
你知道，他们为什么会这样？
right but I I fully owned it and and
但我完全承认了自己的错误。就像
then like even in my relationship like I
我之前说的，即使在我的感情关系中，
said I'm learning how to be a better
我也在学习如何成为一个更好的
boyfriend I'm learning how to be a
男朋友，学习如何……
better listener I'm learning how to
我正在学习如何更好地倾听，如何
resolve conflict better like bear with
更好地解决冲突。请别介意，我一个人
me but I can't do it alone like I need
做不到。我需要
you to point it out you know I need you
你指出我的错误，你知道吗？我需要你
to tell me when I get it wrong or I need
告诉我我什么时候错了，或者
you to tell me you know and so my my
告诉我我什么时候说错了。所以，我
girlfriend and I we got really good at
和我的女朋友在这方面变得非常擅长，
other like when we slipped up so like
比如互相指出对方的错误。
when one of us we were having a
当我们进行
difficult conversation we're having an
艰难的对话，发生争吵时，我
argument and I'm saying my feelings and
表达我的感受，
she would correct my facts and I'd be
她会纠正我的事实，我会说：“
like babe don't correct my facts I just
亲爱的，别纠正我的事实，我只是在
just telling my feelings and she'd be
表达我的感受。”她会说：“
like you're right you're right like so
你说得对，你说得对。”所以
we both took the education so we could
我们都接受了这方面的教育，所以
like we both knew the we both knew the
我们都了解相关的知识，
curriculum so we could both like we
所以我们从来不会把对方的批评放在心上。
never we didn't take it personally if
如果
the other person just helped block and
对方在争吵中帮忙纠正，我们都会很感激。
this led to all kinds of remarkable
这激发了我们各种非凡的
creativity so I'll give you one example
创造力。我举个例子来说明
of of creativity because what happens is
创造力，因为
when you learn the
当你掌握了这些
skills you become hyper aware of how
技巧后，你会对
people are speaking and how you're
别人说话的方式以及你
speaking in the situation you're not
在特定情况下的说话方式变得异常敏感。 你不再只是
just arguing you're not just trying to
争论，不再只是试图证明自己是对的，
be right you're not just trying to
不再只是试图
defend or prove the other person wrong
维护或证明对方是错的，而是会
you actually become hyper aware and you
变得异常清醒，你会
you gain a situational awareness like
获得一种超强的情境意识，
it's kind of amazing so my girlfriend
这简直太神奇了。我
and I were having pretty bad argument
和我女朋友当时吵得很厉害，大概是这样的：我说“
and it went something like this here's
这是
what I did right and here's what you did
我做对的”，我说“这是你
wrong the response was well here's what
做错的”。对方回应说：“这是
I did right and here's what you did
我做对的”，我说“这是你做错的”。对方又
I did right in fact here's two things I
我做对的，实际上，我做对了两件事，
did right and here's four things you did
你做错了四件事”。就这样没完没了地争论下去，显然毫无进展，而且越来越
heated it's getting more aggressive
激烈，越来越咄咄逼人，
it's getting more personal and and I had
越来越人身攻击。我当时
the situational awareness to realize
意识到
this is this is a lose lose situation
这是一个双输的局面，
and I literally interrupted I said okay
于是我直接打断了他们，我说：“好了，
hey I'm interrupting our
我打断你们的
argument and I'm making new rules okay
争论，我要制定新的规则。
currently what we're doing is I'm
现在我们互相指责，我告诉你我做对了什么，我
telling you the things I did right and
告诉你你做错了什么，你也
I'm telling you the things you did wrong
告诉你我做错了什么，
and you're doing the same I'm changing
我要改变
the rules new rules I'm going to tell
规则。” 规则是这样的：我要告诉
you the things that I did wrong and I'm
你我做错的地方，也要
going to tell you the things that you
告诉你你
did right I'm going to go first and then
做对的地方。我先说，然后
you're going to go okay here's what I
你接着说：“好，这是我
got wrong and here's what you got right
做错的地方，这是你做对的地方。”
and she goes well yeah well here's what
她接着说：“嗯，嗯，这是
I got wrong and here's what you got
我做错的地方，这是你做对的地方。”然后我说：“嗯，嗯，这是
right and I well well here's what I got
我
wrong and in four minutes we were joking
做错的地方。”四分钟后，我们开始开玩笑、
and laughing and hugging and realizing
大笑、拥抱，意识到
that we were contributing to the tension
我们都在加剧紧张气氛，
but also the other person was really
但对方也很
trying interesting it's a nice reverse
努力。这很有意思，这是一个不错的反向练习，你可以试试。
try that out and literally it was only
事实上，正是
from all of these classes and skills and
通过所有这些课程、技能和反复
practice and practice that I at least
练习，我才至少
had the sensibility to recognize the
具备了在中途
situation I was in to change the rules
改变规则的意识。
Midway because I think part of the
因为我认为
problem is even if you have the skills
问题的一部分在于，即使你拥有这些技能，
sometimes we forget to um deploy them
有时我们也会忘记运用它们。
that's how to be a remarkable listener I
这就是如何成为一名优秀的倾听者。我
always reflect on this conversation I
总是会想起我和朱利安·特雷泽（J.J.T.）的对话，他是一位TED演讲家，曾发表过一篇
speech about how to be a great speaker
关于如何成为一名优秀演讲者的著名演讲。
and he said he also did a he said that
他说： 他还说，他
that talk on how to be a great speaker
关于如何成为一名优秀演讲者的演讲获得了
did like 30 40 million views and then he
三四千万的点击量，然后他又
did a talk on how to be a great listener
做了一个关于如何成为一名优秀倾听者的演讲，点击量只有
and it did like 3 million views like
三百万，好像
nobody wanted to listen to that um
没人想听似的。嗯，真是讽刺，不是吗？
ironic isn't it it's so ironic but um
太讽刺了。嗯，
that's how to be a great listener to
这就是如何成为一名优秀倾听者的演讲。关于
how to be a great speaker we touched on
如何成为一名优秀演讲者的话题，我们已经谈到了
a couple of points there is there any
一些要点。
as advice if I was going up on stage and
如果我要上台演讲，
I wanted to be able to connect with
想与
people influence them and you know share
听众建立联系，影响他们，并分享
my
我的
message value narrative stories right I
信息，比如价值、叙事和故事，你还有什么更专业的建议吗？我的
mean
意思是，谈论这些都显得很
it's I mean it's so Hackney to even talk
老套，对吧？
about it right right but nobody wants to
但是没人喜欢
be explained to right um people will
被解释，对吧？人们会
listen to stories and remember stories
听故事，记住故事，
they will forget
他们会忘记
explanations and they won't learn from
解释，也不会从
explanations the explanation and the
解释中学习。解释、
facts and the figures can come
事实和数据可以稍后再说，
afterwards but metaphors stories things
但比喻、故事以及那些能
that help people understand what you're
帮助人们理解你想
trying to say then ex then so most
表达的内容的东西才是关键。例如，大多数
people get it backwards first they tell
人会本末倒置，先
you the explanation then they use the
解释，然后再讲故事。 用
metaphor the story to prove the facts
故事这个比喻来证明事实。
I've learned that the total total
我发现，完全
opposite is actually much more effective
相反的方法实际上更有效。
tell the story suck people in they'll
讲故事吸引人，他们会
remember the story and then tell them
记住故事，然后再告诉他们
the Salient bits so for example um and
重点。例如，
all of my work I start with story right
我的所有作品都是从故事开始的。
um so for example if I'm introducing
比如，如果我要介绍
finite infinite games right um I will
有限-无限博弈，我会
say something like
说，在
um during the Vietnam war um most people
越南战争期间，大多数人
don't realize that the United States
没有意识到美国
actually won most of the battles it
实际上赢得了它参与的大部分战役。不仅如此，
battles if you look at the numbers
如果你看看数字，
America lost 58,000 troops over the
美国在10年的战争中损失了58000名士兵，而
Vietnamese lost 3 million people which
北越损失了300万人。这
raises a really interesting question how
引出了一个非常有趣的问题：
do you win all the battles and decimate
你怎么能赢得所有战役，重创
your enemy and lose the war clearly
敌人，却输掉战争？显然，
winning and losing what are you doing
胜利和失败的定义不止一种。你在做什么？
there you're making me curious you're
你让我好奇，你
creating a curiosity Gap you're you you
制造了一个好奇心。你
know I'm emotionally connected to this
知道，我
now or I'll tell you the story when I
现在对此很感兴趣。或者，我可以给你讲讲我
went to Afghanistan you know and how I
去阿富汗的故事，以及我是如何
learned what true purpose means where
领悟到战争的真正意义的。 这意味着
I'll tell you the story of the the A10
我会讲述A-10
pilot Johnny Bravo who risked his life
飞行员约翰尼·布拉沃的故事，他为了他人冒着生命危险。在
rhetorical question at the end of that
这个精彩的故事结尾，我会提出一个反问句：
amazing story you know in the military
你知道，在军队里，
they give medals to people who are
他们会给那些
willing to sacrifice themselves That
愿意牺牲自己以造福
Others May gain and in business we give
他人的人颁发勋章；在商界，我们会给那些
bonuses to people who willing to
愿意
sacrifice others so that we may
牺牲他人以换取自身利益的人发放奖金。
gain I doing like and so all of these
我就是这么做的。所有这些都是为了
things are ways of making people relate
让人们将自己的
their experiences in their lives to my
人生经历与我的
stories I want them to go yeah so it's
故事联系起来。我希望他们能说：是的，这
no longer about me and my facts and my
不再是关于我、我的事实和我的
point of view it's about us and our
观点，而是关于我们、我们
shared journey and our collective
共同的旅程和我们共同的
experience people are interested in
经历。人们对那些
things that make them feel something
能让他们产生某种感受的事物感兴趣，
curiosity is a
好奇心就是一种感觉。
feeling um data isn't going to do that
数据做不到这一点，
data is not going to do that it's like
数据做不到这一点。这就像你
try arguing with somebody with data you
试着用数据去和别人争论一样，你
know try try try try using facts to
知道，试着用事实去
prove your girlfriend wrong when you're
证明你女朋友错了，而你们当时正
having an emotional argument
处于情绪化的争论中，那肯定
then it's not going to go well right and
不会有好结果，对吧？
I think we make this mistake all the
我认为我们总是犯这样的错误，我们总是把
data to an emotional gunfight it's never
数据带到一场情绪化的枪战中。 事情永远不会
going to go
一帆风顺，
well data has to meet data and emotion
数据必须与数据相契合，情感也
has to meet emotion and good leaders and
必须与情感相契合。优秀的领导者和
good presenters know how to modulate and
演讲者懂得如何调节情绪，
so I want people to be emotionally
所以我希望人们能
invested in whatever I have to tell them
对我所讲述的内容投入情感。最
and the easiest way to do that is with a
简单的方法就是讲
story a story that produces some sort of
故事，一个能引发某种
emotion a story that allows people to
情感的故事，一个能让人们产生
relate and even if it's nothing to do
共鸣的故事。即使故事内容与实际无关，比如
like if I'm telling a story of an Air
我讲的是一位空军飞行员的故事，
Force pilot at some point they'll go
他们也会在某个时刻说：“是
yeah I want to work with people like
啊，我也想和这样的人一起工作。”
that too you know um because I even say
因为我甚至说过
that I want to work with people like
我想和这样的人一起工作。
that MH um um how do I get that at work
嗯……如果我不在军队，我该如何在工作中获得这样的机会呢？你呢？
you're speaking now I can see that you
你刚才说话的时候，我注意到你的
have like intonations in your voice
语调很有抑扬顿挫，时而低沉时而高亢，嗯……
mhm these like technical body language
这些都是一些技巧性的肢体语言。还有什么
things what else what other advice would
其他建议吗？
you so when I tell people I'm an
当我告诉别人我是个
introvert they go that's impossible you
内向的人时，他们会说：“这不可能，你
you're a public speaker how can you be
可是个公众演说家，你怎么可能是个
an introvert and what they misunderstand
内向的人？” 他们误解了什么？
is that is that one thing is unrelated
也就是说，这两件事看似无关，
to the other but more important that
但更重要的是，
being an introvert actually makes me a
内向实际上让我成为了一个
better public speaker because I don't
更好的公众演讲者，因为我不
like holding Court I like talking to an
喜欢高谈阔论，我喜欢与
individual and so when I'm on a stage I
人一对一地交谈。所以，当我在台上时，我会
look at one person in the eye and I give
看着一个人的眼睛，向他/她
them an entire sentence or an entire
完整地表达一句话或一个完整的
thought and then I'll go to somebody
想法，然后再转向
else and I'll give them an entire
另一个人，同样地表达
sentence or an entire thought I just
一句话或一个完整的想法。我
make sure to do something called
确保做到“
painting the edges which is I make sure
覆盖边缘”，也就是确保我的目光能够落在观众席的
that I'll get somebody in the upper left
左上角、左下角、右上角、右下角、
right the back middle the front middle
后排中间和前排中间，
not necessarily in an order but I just
顺序不一定固定，但我会
make sure to make eye contact with
确保与
somebody in each area of the audience
观众席每个区域的人都有眼神交流。就像
and I have an like I said and by the way
我刚才说的，这种方法
it works in meetings too if you're
在会议中也同样适用。如果你和
sitting meeting with half a dozen people
五六个人开会，无论
whatever it is you're telling them look
你要说什么，都要看着
somebody in the eye give them an entire
某个人的眼睛，向他/她完整地表达
sentence or an entire thought and look
一句话或一个完整的想法，然后看着他/她的眼睛。你
you and I you can feel it you can feel
我都能感受到
that connection so I did an experiment I
这种联系。所以我做了一个实验，我
was standing on a stage like a thousand
站在一个大约有上千人的台子上……
people whatever it was and I was just
我刚才在
doing Q&amp;A and somebody was asking about
做问答环节，有人问到关于
speaking and I was telling them about
演讲的问题，我就跟他们讲了
eye contact and giving an entire
眼神交流，以及如何把一整
sentence and or entire thought to one
句话或一个完整的想法都集中到一个
person and I picked just a random person
人身上。我随机选了一位
in the audience and I looked at them and
观众，看着他
said okay I'm going to keep talking to
说：“好，我会一直跟
you I'm going to look you in the eye I'm
你说话，我会看着你的眼睛，我会
going to keep talking to you until you
一直跟你说话，直到你
feel a connection and all I want you to
感觉跟我建立了联系。我希望你做的就是，
do is I will keep looking at you and
我会一直看着你，跟
talking to you and I want you to raise
你说话，
your hand when you feel some sort of you
当你感觉跟我建立了某种联系时，就举手。”结果，
around that person all raised their hand
那个人周围大概有八个人都举起了手。
and that's why works because I'm
这就是这个方法有效的原因，因为我
actually connecting with everybody even
实际上和每个人都建立了联系，
though I'm only actually looking at a
即使我只看着其中
few MH um so eye contact as opposed to
几个人。所以，眼神交流，而不是像
scanning and
扫视和
panning like talk to a
移动视线那样，要和人说话，要和人说话，
person talk to a person and the same in
在
a meeting talk to a person make it feel
会议中也是如此，要让对方感觉
like you're talking to them most of us
你是在和他们说话。我们大多数人在这方面都做得
are very bad at that we we don't we we
不好，我们总是
sort of scan and Pan the whole time the
扫视和移动视线。
other thing you said earlier which kind
你之前提到的另一点，
of I've overlayed with that which I've
我
noticed in you is that vulnerability is
注意到你也有，我把它和这个方法结合起来了。 这种脆弱感是
another way to make your message really
让你的信息真正
land and to feel connected to what
触动人心、与
you're saying and you do that well
你所说的话产生共鸣的另一种方式，你做得很好，
because you'll often bring it back to
因为你经常会把话题拉回到
you and your feelings and you'll share
你自己和你的感受上，你会
things with people that others might not
与人分享一些其他人可能不会
share MH and that for some reason makes
分享的事情。不知何故，这反而让
your message even more powerful well I
你的信息更有力量。我
don't think of myself as special and
不认为自己很特殊，
even though I'm standing on a stage I
即使我站在台上，我也
don't think of myself as talking down to
不会觉得自己是在居高临下地对
people and so one of the big things that
人说话。所以
I do on purpose is I use we instead of
我刻意做的一件事就是用“我们”而不是“
you unless there's a very specific
你”，除非有非常具体的
reason why not to so for example I'll
原因。例如，我永远不会
say I'll never I'll I'll never say you
说“你
need to do everything in your power to
需要竭尽全力去
live a life of service because until you
服务他人”，因为“除非你
learn to live a life of service you will
学会服务他人，否则你永远不会
never find
找到
happiness you will never hear those
幸福”。你永远不会听到我说出这样的
words come out of my mouth I'll say
话。我会说，
things we need to all learn how to do
我们都需要学习如何去做那些能让
the things that give us a sense of
我们感受到
service because none of us will ever
服务他人的事情，因为
find happiness until we learn to live
除非我们学会服务他人，否则我们永远不会找到幸福。
lives of service I'm on the same Journey
我和你们一样，也在经历同样的旅程，我也
I'm on I have the same struggles I am
有同样的挣扎，我并不
imperfect and bumbling myself and so how
完美。 我自己都笨手笨脚的，怎么
dare I stand on the stage and tell
敢站在台上告诉
people what they need to do when I
别人该怎么做呢？我
haven't got it all figured out myself
自己都还没完全搞清楚呢。
yet right I will share what I'm learning
我会分享我
on my journey but we are going on this
在这段旅程中学到的东西，但我们会
journey together shoulder Tosh shoulder
肩并肩地一起走下去，
side by side and you will teach me
你会教我一些
things and I will teach you things but
东西，我也会教你一些东西，但
I'm in it and so I one of the reasons I
我始终身在其中。所以，我
think my work connects with people is I
认为我的作品能引起人们共鸣的原因之一是，我
don't think that I'm above anyone I
不觉得自己高人一等，我
think I'm right in it with it and I do I
认为我完全融入其中。
come up I come as a student and I share
我以学生的身份来到这里，分享我在这段
what I'm learning on my journey and I
旅程中学到的东西。我从
and I and I learn from questions and I
问题中学习，从评论中学习，从
people and I learn from the debates I
人们身上学习，从辩论中学习，
have and I learn from the discussions I
从讨论中学习，
have and I love it um all of my works
我热爱这一切。嗯，我所有的作品都
are incomplete and
尚未完成。 虽然并不
imperfect but they're they're steps
完美，但这些都是
forward Simon we have a closing
进步。西蒙，我们
tradition on this podcast where the last
这个播客有个结束的传统，上一位
guest leaves a question for the next
嘉宾会给下一位嘉宾留下一个问题，而下一位嘉宾
guest not knowing who they're going to
并不知道问题会留给谁。
been left for
留给
you
你的问题
is what area of your life do you still
是：你觉得生活中哪个方面还
think you need some good advice on
需要一些好的建议？
I mean
我的意思是，我
it's I mean every area of my life I've
生活的方方面面我都搞不清楚。
out I don't understand
我不懂
Finance I mean I'm kind of an idiot when
金融，在这方面我简直是个白痴。
it comes to that stuff and I sit in
我参加各种
these meetings and people talk to me
会议，人们跟我讲那些专业
with jargon and I literally I feel so
术语，我感觉自己像个
dumb you know uh my mind just doesn't my
傻瓜。你知道，我的
brain just doesn't work that way but um
大脑就是不理解这些。但是，嗯，你知道，我正在
yeah I mean I'm I'm I'm learning to
努力
understand some of the stuff that I'm
理解一些我
supposed to know you know
应该知道的东西，包括一些
literally personal things or no I mean
个人方面的事情，或者
work things like like like deal making
工作方面的事情，比如交易谈判。我完全
like I don't understand any of it like
不懂这些。就像
you and I were talking before the camera
你我之前在摄像机
started rolling like about valuations
开始拍摄之前聊到的估值，我有点
understand I mean this is one of the
明白了。这真的很
really interesting things is I think our
有趣。 我认为我们的
success kind of correlates to us even
成功与我们
admitting that there's things we don't
承认自己不
understand I think the greatest
理解某些事情密切相关。我曾与一些最伟大的
entrepreneurs that I've sat here with um
企业家交流，他们之所以
are great because they're very good at
伟大，是因为他们非常善于
knowing what they absolutely don't know
认识到自己的不足。
I remember Richard Branson telling me
我记得理查德·布兰森
when he was on my podcast in New York he
在纽约参加我的播客节目时告诉我，
was saying um he' built like the biggest
他创建了
one of the biggest groups in Europe
欧洲最大的集团之一——
called The Virgin group and he was like
维珍集团。当时他大约
55 years old and sat in a meeting with
55岁，在一次与
his directors and they looked at him and
董事们的会议上，董事们看着他说：“
said Richard you don't know what profit
理查德，你不知道什么
is do you and he goes no yeah he didn't
是利润，对吧？”他回答说：“是的，我不懂。
understand I read a p&amp;l yeah and so they
我读过损益表。”于是他们把
took him outside of a room he said to me
他带到房间外，他告诉我，
that they drew a picture of an ocean and
他们用蜡笔画了一幅海洋的图画。
with crayons he said use the word
他们说：“用
crayons and he said they drew a net in
蜡笔这个词来形容海洋。”然后他们在海洋里画了一张网，
the ocean and put fishies in the net and
把小鱼放进网里。他们
said Richard the fishies in the net you
说：“理查德，网里的鱼归你，这就是
get to keep that that's your net profit
你的净利润。”
Richard goes got it and the fact that he
理查德明白了。事实上，他能够在对
business without knowing the basics and
基本概念一无所知的情况下，建立起如此庞大的商业帝国。
he goes I go why and he goes well
他说，我问为什么，他说，好吧，
because in in his business because I'm a
因为在他的生意里，因为我是个有阅读
dyslexic thinker he said I've always
障碍的思考者，他说我总是只
just like asked who not how yeah I've
问“谁”，而不是“怎么做”。是的，
just I've always had to delegate yeah
我总是不得不把事情委托出去。是的，
and a lot of people I I but I I'm the
很多人都这样，但我也
same like I I I know what I don't
一样，我知道自己不
know and I trust myself when I know
知道什么，我知道的事情我会相信自己，不知道的事情
things and I don't trust myself when I
我不相信自己。
don't know things the mistakes I've made
我犯过的错误，
and the and I've made the same mistake
而且我犯过好几次同样的错误，这
over a few times which it causes me a
让我有点
bit of self-loathing
自我厌恶。
um which is when I didn't understand
嗯，就是当我不理解
something and my insecurity about not
某些事情的时候，我对不
knowing that thing made me overly trust
知道这件事的不安全感让我过度信任
somebody who claimed that they would
那些声称会
guide me and help me and they did know
指导我、帮助我的人，而他们确实知道
the thing that I didn't know and the
我不知道的事情。
mistake that I made was I never really
我犯的错误是，我从来没有真正
like those people or trusted those
喜欢过这些人，也没有真正信任过这些
people but because their skill set um
人，但因为他们的技能可以
you know bolstered mine I let them tell
增强我的技能，所以我让他们告诉
me what to do and I did what they told
我该怎么做，我照做了。结果
me and 100% of those times I got [__]
100%的情况下我都吃了亏，
and those people um ended up taking
这些人最终都占了我的
advantage of me what's the lesson um
便宜。 对我来说，你学到的教训是什么？我的
that you've learned my the lesson is
教训是
trust my gut right which is and I don't
相信我的直觉，对吧？我并不是
mean to make my own decisions about
说要事事都自己做决定，
everything but if I if I believe the
但如果我相信一个比
who knows more than me literally about
我懂得多的人给我的建议，即使我对某些
something I don't
我不
understand and if it
理解的事情了解得更多，即使
feels wrong it doesn't mean the advice
感觉不对，也不意味着这个建议
is necessarily wrong find a different
一定是错的，那就换
person yeah and so I the mistake I made
个人。是的，所以我犯的错误
was rejecting all advice that felt wrong
是拒绝所有感觉不对的建议。
no no no you can't do that but what I
不，不，不，你不能那样做。但我
have learned is to reject the people who
学到的是，要拒绝那些
feel wrong and that's the lesson and I
感觉不对的人，这就是教训。我
wish I knew that then I wouldn't have
希望我早点明白这一点，那样我就不会
made some of the some of the worst
犯下职业
mistakes I've made in my career um
生涯中一些最严重的错误了。很
unfortunately taught me that lesson so
不幸，这件事教会了我这个教训。真
interesting and the thing that annoys me
有趣。让我恼火的
is I made it more than once I had a
是，我不止一次犯过这样的错误。
meeting yesterday where the guy
昨天开会的时候，那个人给
presented something to me and knew so
我做了一个演示，他对这个
much more about that than me the subject
主题了解得比我多得多。
and my I just didn't my body just didn't
我就是感觉
connect with him in some way and I found
和他没有共鸣，我发现
myself questioning something I didn't
自己在质疑一些我不了解的东西。是的，一个
know yeah a subject I didn't know but as
我不了解的主题。
I walked out the meeting i' go no it was
我走出会议室，我说不，是那
the guy you didn't you didn't like
个人，你不喜欢
something what does waren Buffett say
什么？沃伦·巴菲特说过什么来着？
you can't make good deals with bad
你不可能和坏人做成好交易。是
people yeah you know exactly and cuz I
啊，你懂的。因为我
do deals with people who know a lot they
跟那些懂行的人做生意，他们
they could take advantage of me I have
可能会占我便宜。
people that I've worked with that
我以前合作过的人，他们
absolutely could bamboozle me
绝对可以骗我，
um but they
但他们
didn't you know because they're good
没有，因为他们是
people because they're good people this
好人，因为他们是好人。
is unfortunately why we have
不幸的是，这就是为什么我们需要
lawyers is because you need you know
律师，因为你需要，你知道，
people will take advantage of you and
人们会占你便宜，这很
it's it's sad you and I both know this
可悲。你我都明白，
which is the best deals you you you go
最好的交易就是找律师，
with the lawyers and you Rumble and you
你和律师一起，
you go through all the terms but once
你仔细审查所有条款，但一旦
the deal is signed you'll never look at
合同签了，你这辈子都不会再看
that contract again for the rest of your
那份合同。
life and if you did I can guarantee you
如果你看了，我可以保证
that both sides have breached that
双方都违反了
contract and violated the terms multiple
合同，多次违反了条款，
times but you don't care because you
但你不在乎，因为你们
trust each other you know that a
彼此信任。你知道，
horribly sour if you refer to the
如果你们再去看
contract well according to the
合同，根据
contract that deal is done yeah because
合同，那笔交易就彻底失败了。 是的，因为
great business relationships you never
良好的商业关系意味着你永远不会
pull the contract out ever you've and
撕毁合同，
you break it all the time pay late work
你总是违约，拖欠工资，工作时间
too many hours take advantage of each
过长，互相占便宜，
other overuse things nobody
滥用资源，但没人会
cares because there's trust Simon thank
在意，因为彼此信任。西蒙，
you so much I am if people haven't seen
非常感谢你。如果还有人没看过，
it yet people haven't checked it out I
没了解过，我
highly recommend everybody go and check
强烈建议大家去
out the optimism company because your um
看看“乐观公司”（The Optimism Company），因为
all the things that you've talked about
你今天谈到的所有事情，
today and all the skills that I think
以及我认为
are deficient in society and even the
社会上普遍缺乏的技能，甚至包括
idea of how to like how to the win
如何赢得
friends um influence people listen
朋友、影响他人、更好地倾听、更好地
better communicate better so that we can
沟通，从而
resolve problems and move in the same
解决问题并朝着同一个
direction all of those things are taught
方向前进——所有这些都在“
and answered on the at the optimism
乐观公司”得到教授和解答。
company I kind of look at it as like a
我把它看作是一所
modern University that's filling the
现代大学，它正在弥补
deficit of skills that the uh all of us
我们所有人（
I was going to say the younger
我本来想说年轻
Generations but it's really all of us
一代，但实际上是我们所有人）
have started to either disregard or lose
开始忽视或遗忘的技能缺陷。
in a world where education is teaching
在这个教育
us so little about how what it is to be
很少教我们如何成为
a successful human being and friend and
一个成功的人和朋友的世界里，这真是太好了。
you've created a business that Endeavors
你的合作伙伴、同事和领导创建了一家致力于
to fill that hole um it's remarkable
填补这一空白的企业，这真是太棒了，
it's really really actionable um great
它真的非常实用。
optimism company and it's delivered in
乐观公司拥有非常有经验的优秀教师，而且授课方式
such
非常
a a friendly way and when I say friendly
友好。我说友好，是指它对
I mean friendly to a brain like mine
像我这样
that is that isn't tremendously patient
不太有耐心的人也很友好。
so I recommend everybody go and check it
所以我推荐大家去
out I'll link it below as well and we're
看看，链接也在下面。我们都
all very excited for your next book
非常期待你的下一本书，
about friend oh that's very nice of you
关于朋友。哦，你真好，
thank you I love coming on here I always
谢谢。我喜欢来这里，总能
learn something I love that we get to
学到东西。我喜欢我们能一起
take an idea and wrestle with it and uh
探讨一个想法，并努力理解它。
and I always appreciate that that you
我一直很欣赏你不断
push uh and you push for the the best
鞭策我，而且你这样做的
reason of all which is because you're
理由是最好的，那就是你
curious to understand more and in so
渴望了解更多。在这个过程中，
doing you always teach me so thanks
你总是能教会我很多东西。
again for having me on it's I I it's
再次感谢你邀请我来，这
always such a joy thank you so much
总是让我感到非常愉快。非常感谢你，
Simon thank
西蒙。
you how many of you started thinking
你们当中有多少人是在30岁的时候开始考虑
about your long-term Health when you hit
长期健康的？
30 for me this was a wakeup moment of me
对我来说，这是一个觉醒的时刻。 我
thinking to myself okay I probably need
心想，好吧，我可能真的需要
to start paying a little bit more
开始更加
attention now I already felt a change in
注意自己的饮食了。我30岁的时候就已经感觉到身体发生了一些变化，
myself when I hit 30 with things like my
比如
metabolism my energy levels so this year
新陈代谢和精力水平。今年
is no different Zoe which is a company
也不例外。Zoe是
I've invested in but also a company that
我投资的一家公司，也是
are a sponsor of this podcast helps me
这个播客的赞助商。它
on their world leading science and my
基于世界领先的科学技术和我
own test results if I'm ordering food I
自己的测试结果，帮助我做出更明智的食物选择。如果我点外卖，我
know how to make my takeaway so much
知道如何让我的外卖更
smarter by adding things like a side of
健康，比如先加一份
vegetables to eat first or choosing the
蔬菜，或者选择
option with the most fiber Zoe helps me
纤维含量最高的选项。Zoe帮助我
to make that choice it gu guides me and
做出这些选择，它指导我、
coaches me it's my personalized
辅导我，就像我的私人
nutrition coach that I have on me 24/7
营养教练一样，24小时伴我左右。
and to help you start your Zoe journey
为了帮助你开启Zoe之旅，
and start making smarter food choices
开始做出更明智的食物选择，
I'm giving you guys 10% off when you
我给你们提供10%的折扣。
join Zoe now all you've got to do is use
现在加入Zoe，只需
code ce10 at the checkout when you sign
在结账时使用代码ce10即可。祝你使用
up enjoy and let me know how you get on
愉快，也请告诉我你的体验。
[Music]
[音乐]
ah
啊